They are currently Riverside Excellence Leagues.
彼らは現在、リバーサイド エクセレンス リーグです。
Please cancel this session.
このセッションをキャンセルしてください。
Please let Mr. Tong Huni ring旦阛
Tong Huni さんにダン阛を鳴らさせてください
and the ambassador
そして大使
receiving the honors of his Korean relationship with the使衿携.
使衿との韓国関係の栄誉を受賞。
Hi, I am Wong Huni-J ק่ Easy to ask
こんにちは、ウォン・フニJです。
Any questions for board members,
理事会メンバーへのご質問は、
this morning I am describing to you
今朝、私はあなたに説明しています
give this speech
このスピーチをする
this subject
このテーマ
He is also very poetic
彼はとても詩的でもあります
epic typhoon
壮大な台風
in science
科学で
And the subtitle didn't win on top
そしてサブタイトルはトップにならなかった
The subtitles are in his hand
字幕は彼の手の中にある
Inaction is something Taiwanese must know
不作為は台湾人が知っておくべきこと
Taiwan is
台湾は
OK this is the subtitle
はい、これがサブタイトルです
Interesting
面白い
Then I add another subtitle
次に、別のサブタイトルを追加します
Typhoon Night Talk Typhoon Room
タイフーンナイトトーク タイフーンルーム
I hope everyone can go home safely
みんなが無事に家に帰れるといいですね
before that started
それが始まる前に
still take this
まだこれを取る
Director Wu introduced to everyone
ウー監督がみんなに紹介
Although there are
ありますが、
but i think
しかし、私は思います
we still want this
私たちはまだこれが欲しいです
Let me introduce this to you
これを紹介しましょう
This Professor Wu Junjie
この呉俊傑教授は
it was 1986
1986年でした
Graduated from the Department of Atmospheric Sciences of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学大気科学科卒業
Then in 1993
そして1993年に
Massachusetts Institute of Technology
マサチューセッツ工科大学
Atmosphere of Earth from MIT
MIT からの地球の大気
and a Ph.D. from the Department of Planetary Sciences
惑星科学科で博士号を取得
then to this
それからこれに
Princeton University Geophysics
プリンストン大学地球物理学
Postdoctoral research in fluid power laboratory
流体力研究室での博士研究員
After returning to Taiwan
台湾帰国後
Worried about doing this research questioned
この研究を行うことに不安がある
Research on typhoons
台風に関する研究
Including the moving strength of the typhoon
台風の移動力も含めて
The Far Wall and the Dynamics of Rainfall
遠い壁と降雨のダイナミクス
Interaction of Typhoon with Terrain and Ocean
台風と地形および海洋の相互作用
and make this strategic observation
そしてこの戦略的な観察を行ってください
It's the wind-chasing project
風を追うプロジェクトです
I still came to ask him yesterday
昨日も聞きに来ました
Their plane flew out again yesterday
彼らの飛行機は昨日また飛び立った
Go to the typhoon show to observe this time
今度は台風ショーを見に行きます
Typhoon Sura and more
台風スーラなど
Research performance is certainly top-notch
研究実績は確かに一流
2007 2009
2007年 2009年
Awarded twice by Taiwan National Science Council
台湾国家科学委員会より2回受賞
Lift research award
リフト研究賞
It's also the one in 2009
こちらも2009年の物です
When the National Science Council was more than 50 years old
国家学術会議が創立50年を超えた頃
also choose this
これも選んでください
One of the 50 scientific achievements of Taiwan
台湾の 50 の科学的成果の 1 つ
Currently in the Department of Atmospheric Sciences
現在、大気科学科に所属
Distinguished Professor and Head of Department
特別教授および学部長
Also serving as the American Meteorological Society's
アメリカ気象協会の委員も務める
tropical weather and
熱帯の気候と
member of the hurricane committee
ハリケーン委員会のメンバー
Also our Republic of China Earth Science Society
私たちの中華民国地球科学協会も
published sets
公開されたセット
editor-in-chief of a scientific journal
科学雑誌の編集長
We welcome with warm applause
温かい拍手でお迎えいたします
Director Wu
ウー監督
Goodnight everybody
おやすみ皆さん
I'm Wu Junjie
私はウー・ジュンジエです
I would like to thank Director Peng for the invitation and the introduction just now
ただいまご招待とご紹介をいただきました彭監督に感謝申し上げます。
Then I feel very honored to be here today
それでは、今日ここに来られてとても光栄に思います
Academia Sinica
中央研究院
And on this typhoon night
そしてこの台風の夜に
see so many
たくさん見る
Our science community or one of our science popularization circles
私たちの科学コミュニティまたは科学普及サークルのいずれか
come with me, let's interact
私と一緒に来て、交流しましょう
I wish I could today
今日できたらいいのに
Shared with you some popular science knowledge and information related to typhoons
台風に関する人気の科学知識や情報をお伝えします
can provide us with useful
私たちに役立つものを提供してくれる
very helpful
非常に役立ちます
Then I will briefly introduce this topic to you.
それでは、この件について簡単にご紹介させていただきます。
The goal given here is a little bit bigger, so I think that when I was concentrating the time in the end
ここで与えられた目標はもう少し大きいので、最終的には時間を集中して取り組んだときだと思います
I think it will mainly focus on the scientific part
主に科学的な部分に焦点を当てることになると思います
that slightly
それはわずかに
If it is mentioned in the introduction I will put my
紹介文で言及されている場合は、私のものを載せます
Some of a book translated a few years ago
数年前に翻訳された本の一部
Take it out as the subject of today's introductory reading, and then gradually enter the theme of typhoon to be discussed today
それを今日の入門書の主題として取り出し、徐々に今日議論する台風のテーマに入っていきます。
OK
OK
That said, I am very touched when the typhoon is coming
とはいえ、台風が近づいているこの時期はとても感動します
This moment of calm before the storm can be gathered here with everyone today
嵐の前の静けさのひとときを今日もみんなでここに集まれます
As Teacher Kun said just now
今クン先生が言ったように
Hope you all come back safe and sound today
今日も皆様が無事に帰ってきますように
I think
私が思うに
Not yet maybe but tomorrow night
まだかもしれないけど明日の夜
Let's start with the typhoon that is about to occur.
まずは、これから発生する台風の話から始めましょう。
You may have noticed that we happen to have a typhoon called Sula.
お気づきかもしれませんが、たまたまスーラと呼ばれる台風が発生しています。
Just off the southeast coast of Taiwan
台湾南東海岸のすぐ沖
already very close
すでに非常に近い
It's only about 300 kilometers away from us now.
今は私たちから300キロほどしか離れていない。
Then this typhoon is gradually approaching the sea off the northeast corner of Taiwan
そして、この台風は徐々に台湾の北東の沖合に近づいています。
Then everyone can see that this is actually in the East today.
そうすれば、これが今日実際に東部にあることが誰でもわかります。
It seems to be doing the weather forecast at seven o'clock now
今、7時の天気予報をやっているようです
The typhoon is already very close to the coast of Taiwan
台風はすでに台湾の沿岸に非常に接近しています
So its airflow also ushers in the rainfall in Huadong area
そのため、その気流が花東地域に降雨をもたらします。
Especially between Yilan and Hualien
特に宜蘭～花蓮間
You can see that there has been a lot of rain
かなりの雨が降ったことがわかります
In fact, the rainfall will gradually increase.
実際、雨量は徐々に増えていくでしょう。
Then the radar echo may mainly see that the rainband is only the periphery
その場合、レーダーエコーでは主にレインバンドが周縁部のみ​​であることがわかる可能性があります。
The main rainbands are actually in the south of the typhoon in Taiwan
主要な降雨帯は実際には台湾の台風の南にあります
Fortunately, these are still in overseas seas
幸いなことに、これらはまだ海外の海にあります
Then this is its cloud and soil and its position
それでは、これがその雲と土とその位置です
In fact there is another typhoon at the same time
実は同じ時期に別の台風も来ています
Taiwan is farther away from Japan in this direction
この方向では台湾は日本から遠いです
Then the typhoon will continue to move northwestward.
この後も台風は北西に進みます。
good
良い
What about the typhoon?
台風はどうですか？
In fact, our Central Meteorological Bureau has also made some official forecasts
実際、中央氣象局もいくつかの公式予報を発表しています。
You can see that this forecast has also been slightly revised in the past few days.
この予測もここ数日で若干修正されていることがわかります。
From the original it was gradually closer to the southern part of Taiwan
当初から徐々に台湾の南に近づいていきました
It became a typhoon to the east of Taiwan two or three days ago
２、３日前に台湾の東で台風になりました
As of yesterday and today, it has been corrected to the northeast corner or the open sea.
昨日と今日の時点では北東の角か外海に修正されています。
Well, although it is impossible for him to cross Taiwan directly
まあ、台湾を直接渡るのは無理だけどね
But if he's around us
でももし彼が私たちの周りにいるなら
This threat may still be quite large, especially the rainfall in the east, northeast and north
この脅威は依然としてかなり大きい可能性があり、特に東部、北東部、北部での降雨量は顕著です。
In fact, it is possible to be very high
実際には非常に高くなる可能性があります
So please pay attention
だから注意してください
In fact, everyone can see that it is Taiwan's prediction that it is actually not read.
実際には読まれていないのは台湾の予測であることは誰の目にも明らかだ。
In fact, the official meteorological units of countries all over the world have done
実際、世界中の国の公式気象単位は次のことを行っています。
Then add that the computer models in each country are predicting
次に、各国のコンピューター モデルが予測していることを付け加えます。
Most of the predictions so far are pretty consistent.
これまでの予測のほとんどはかなり一致しています。
Pointing to typhoon likely to approach Taiwan's northeast corner
台風が台湾の北東隅に接近する可能性を指摘
That's just a prediction of the center of a typhoon
あくまで台風の中心の予想です
But everyone, don't forget that the typhoon itself has a size
でも皆さん、台風自体にも大きさがあることを忘れないでください。
range of hundreds of kilometers
範囲は数百キロメートル
So in fact, our Taiwan will soon be shrouded in its sphere of influence
つまり、実際、私たちの台湾は間もなくその勢力圏に覆い隠されることになるでしょう。
So there are some risks, you may want to pay attention
リスクもあるので注意したほうがいいかもしれません
Of course, the question that everyone may be most concerned about
もちろん、誰もが最も懸念しているであろう質問
This question is one that I cannot answer
この質問は私には答えられない質問です
Otherwise I'm out of touch
そうしないと連絡が取れなくなります
But let me do a simple poll
でも、簡単なアンケートをしてみましょう
If you live in Taipei City, please raise your hand
台北市にお住まいの方は手を挙げてください
Whoa, please raise your hand in New Taipei City
おっと、新北市で手を挙げてください
ok 2 to 1 but almost bigger
まあ2対1だが、ほぼ大きい
Please raise your hand in other counties
他県の方も手を挙げてください
No, but I'm still very impressed that everyone came
いや、でもみんなが来てくれたことにはとても感動してるよ
However, I think there are two people who can help you answer this question.
ただし、この質問に答えるのに役立つ人が 2 人いると思います。
Then please watch this interview tomorrow
それでは明日のこのインタビューをご覧ください
good
良い
what's next
次は何ですか
Let me tell you that we are Taiwan
言っておきますが、私たちは台湾です
I just happened to actually go from the US yesterday.
実は昨日アメリカから行ってきたんです。
Columbia University visit
コロンビア大学訪問
and I did a presentation
そしてプレゼンテーションを行いました
I actually found that report very moving.
実際、私はその報告書が非常に感動的であると感じました。
because of that report
あの報告のせいで
It's about research related to typhoons
台風に関する研究についてです
However, an elderly man in his eighties came
ところが、80代の老人がやって来た。
come and listen to my report
私の報告を聞きに来てください
Then this is called his name is Wallace Broker
それからこれは彼の名前がウォレス・ブローカーと呼ばれます
He's the whole movie after tomorrow
彼は明日以降の映画全体です
messenger of scientific theories
科学理論のメッセンジャー
That is to say why the ocean
それがなぜ海なのかというと、
He will have this master of the so-called gentle circulation
彼にはいわゆる穏やかな循環のマスターがいるだろう
Then when he put forward this hypothesis forty years ago
そして、40年前に彼がこの仮説を提唱したとき、
Many people think it is impossible
無理だと思っている人が多い
it's out of the question
それは話になりません
As a result, he is now the researcher
その結果、彼は現在研究者になっています
the most important issue
最も重要な問題
But very big
でもとても大きい
But the main point is
しかし、重要な点は、
I was on the plane when I got back
帰ってきたら飛行機に乗っていた
Just hear about our nationality airlines
私たちの国籍の航空会社について聞いてください
just playing once
一度遊んだだけ
This song is promoting the prestige of the country and introducing Taiwan
この歌は国の威信を高め、台湾を紹介しています。
You may have heard his song
彼の歌を聞いたことがあるかもしれません
just sing whatever
とにかく何でも歌ってください
she famous
彼女は有名です
have you heard
聞いてますか
In Taiwan, I am fine with him
台湾では彼とは大丈夫です
Do you have
ありますか
This is our treasure island
ここは私たちの宝島です
that was hundreds of years ago
それは何百年も前のことでした
four or five hundred years ago
四五百年前
When these foreign ships pass by
外国船が通りかかるとき
so call our beautiful island
だから私たちの美しい島と呼んでください
that's really beautiful
それは本当に美しいです
there are also many poets
詩人もたくさんいる
Describe our island in beautiful verse
私たちの島を美しい詩で説明してください
There are mountains, seas, winds and clouds
山があり、海があり、風があり、雲がある
That's all introduced here
ここで紹介したのはここまでです
so very beautiful
とても美しい
But although we live on this beautiful island
でも、私たちはこの美しい島に住んでいるのに、
But of course it's also nature's creation
でももちろんそれも自然の創造物です
We happen to be in an area with a lot of environmental hazards
私たちはたまたま環境上の危険が多い地域にいます
that is undeniable
それは否定できない
we who live on this island
この島に住む私たち
It must also be beneficial for this
これにも有益なはずです
have a certain understanding
一定の理解を持っている
Especially when we face several very large natural disasters
特にいくつかの非常に大きな自然災害に直面したとき
One is that we all know that the Pacific Rim
1つは、私たちは皆、環太平洋地域であることを知っているということです。
This is the whole volcanic and seismic zone right here.
これがここの火山帯と地震帯全体です。
What about the other side?
反対側はどうですか？
is almost the only place where the most active typhoons in the Northwest Pacific must pass.
北西太平洋で最も活発な台風が通過しなければならないほぼ唯一の場所です。
If I list the trajectories of these typhoon layers in this picture
この写真にこれらの台風層の軌跡を列挙すると
You can see that Taiwan is at the middle point of its final path.
台湾が最終的な進路の中間点にあることがわかります。
The Philippines, a little to the south, is actually quite serious.
少し南にあるフィリピンは、実はかなり深刻です。
I happened to be eating
たまたま食べてた
Also with a listener who is Mr. Liang
リスナーの梁さんも一緒に
Also mentioned that he said he was also affected by the typhoon
台風の影響も受けたとのことにも言及
Affected his itinerary to visit the Philippines
フィリピン訪問の旅程に影響
Then you can see us in the Philippines
そしたらフィリピンでお会いしましょう
Whether it's the Philippines
フィリピンだろうが
or Taiwan is here
それとも台湾はここですか
I'll just call it this aisle called Typhoon
この通路をタイフーンと呼ぶことにする
then i have to be careful
それなら気をつけないといけない
We also have to take precautions against typhoons, which can cause disasters.
災害を引き起こす可能性がある台風にも注意が必要です。
And we have many in Taiwan
台湾にもたくさんあります
There is more rainfall due to the mountains
山のせいで雨が多くなる
Then the possibility of self-disaster is even greater.
そうなると、自己災害の可能性はさらに高まります。
What if we look at some external data?
外部データを見てみるとどうなるでしょうか?
Disaster In fact it is a
災害 実はそれは
Many This is a World Bank report in 2005
これは 2005 年の世界銀行の報告書です。
He divides this main disaster atmosphere into six categories
彼はこの主な災害の雰囲気を 6 つのカテゴリーに分類しています
For example, including earthquakes and volcanoes
例えば、地震や火山などです。
This is called landslide
これを土砂崩れといいます
That is, there are still floods, sweat disasters and storms
つまり、今でも洪水、汗災害、嵐が続いているということです。
Then among the six major disasters
六大災害のうち
What percentage of the population is in each country in the world
世界の各国には人口の何パーセントがいますか
under his influence
彼の影響下で
Ninety percent of our population in Taiwan
台湾の人口の90パーセント
are affected by at least two hazards
少なくとも 2 つの危険の影響を受けている
Seventy-three percent of the population also lives in
人口の 73% が次の地域に住んでいます。
Areas affected by three hazards
3つの危険にさらされる地域
So we are paving the way in relatively high-risk areas
したがって、私たちは比較的リスクの高い領域に道を切り開いています
If this picture is used to show
この写真が展示に使用される場合
you see our eyes
私たちの目が見えますね
It is one of the few red zones in the world.
世界でも数少ないレッドゾーンのひとつです。
This is an analysis of a company from last year
これは昨年の企業の分析です
It also highlights that
また、それは次のことを強調しています
There are several economic activities in the world
世界にはさまざまな経済活動が存在します
Those who received this very serious extreme disaster
この大変甚大な災害を受けられた方々
Countries exposed to impact
影響にさらされている国
These regions rank fourth in the world
これらの地域は世界で第 4 位にランクされています
except Taiwan
台湾を除く
The United States, Japan, and mainland China
米国、日本、中国本土
So we have to guard against typhoons
だから私たちは台風に注意しなければなりません
because we're in it
私たちはその中にいるから
Then start entering today's regime is a typhoon
それから今日の政権に入り始めてください、それは台風です
We are indeed talking about Taiwan
まさに台湾のことを話しているのです
On average, we have nearly four typhoons a year
平均すると、1年にほぼ4回の台風が発生します
will attack us
私たちを攻撃するだろう
plus although the damage it caused
それに、それが引き起こしたダメージはあるものの、
in fact it is obvious
実際それは明らかです
This average is just a direct loss
この平均は直接的な損失です
It can probably reach NT$17.4 billion
おそらく174億台湾ドルに達する可能性がある
In fact, both are more than 0.5
実際には両方とも0.5を超えています
3% of nationally produced cats
国内で生産される猫の3％
on the other hand
一方で
We know that disasters caused by typhoons will cause floods
台風による災害は洪水を引き起こすことを私たちは知っています
In fact, if the typhoon does not come
実際、台風が来なければ
There will be drought in Taiwan
台湾では干ばつが起こるだろう
So it's still very scary for us
だから、それは私たちにとって今でもとても怖いことなのです
but can't live without it
でもそれなしでは生きていけない
That leads us to the question
それは私たちに質問をもたらします
is to pay great attention
細心の注意を払うことです
What I will tell you again is that in recent years
もう一度言いますが、ここ数年は
Disasters caused by typhoons and floods
台風や洪水による災害
What about some changes that affect us
私たちに影響を与えるいくつかの変化についてはどうでしょうか
if we start here now
今ここから始めれば
in 1990
1990年に
It was that year, in fact, it was against Taiwan
実はその年は台湾との対戦だった
The year with the most typhoons
台風が最も多かった年
A kind of eight typhoons
8つの台風の一種
It is the record-breaking typhoon affecting Taiwan
台湾に影響を与える記録的な台風です
Some of them are particularly serious
そのうちのいくつかは特に深刻です
is the dean
学部長です
it was 2001
それは2001年でした
yes this is 2001
はい、これは 2001 年です
In 2001 there were two
2001年には2件あった
Two of the larger
大きい方の2つ
One is Peach Juice and the other is Nali
1つはピーチジュース、もう1つはナリです。
at that time
その時
since that year
その年以来
The entire country of Taiwan has made a more planned disaster prevention and beach prevention measure.
台湾全土では、より計画的な防災・海岸対策が講じられています。
So in later years we can also see
したがって、後年、私たちはまた見ることができます
Although there are many severe or heavy typhoons passing by
猛烈な台風や強い台風がたくさん通過していますが、
real casualties
実際の犠牲者
In particular, the number of deaths has been greatly reduced
特に死者数は大幅に減った
So it seems that our active warning at that time
したがって、当時の私たちの積極的な警告は
These actions related to the so-called evacuation of these dangerous areas
これらの危険地域からのいわゆる避難に関連する行為
All have helped to reduce the disaster and casualties
すべてが災害と死傷者の軽減に貢献しました
But in 1997
しかし1997年に
the past 45 years
過去45年間
The number of people has increased again
また人が増えた
Of course there is a special case because of the Morakot typhoon
もちろん、モラコット台風のため特別なケースがあります
but no matter what
でも何があっても
After analyzing it, the scientists found that
それを分析した結果、科学者たちは次のことを発見しました。
Disasters in recent years are more of the so-called compound type
近年の災害はいわゆる複合型が多い
It is caused by the combination of elements of many different disasters
さまざまな災害の要素が組み合わさって引き起こされる
It's worth preventing
防ぐ価値はある
Its standard procedure is even more rigorous
その標準手順はさらに厳格です
Or to keep up with the changes in this disaster
あるいは、この災害の変化に対応するため
to cope with it
それに対処するために
Let me show you a few examples
いくつかの例をお見せしましょう
An example you may be familiar with
あなたがよく知っているかもしれない例
What about this example of Typhoon Morakot?
この台風モラコットの例はどうでしょうか？
means it happened with a very high rainfall
非常に高い降雨量で起こったことを意味します
Within a limited period of about 3 to 5 days
3日～5日程度の限られた期間内で
What about the super high rainfall?
超多雨の場合はどうなるでしょうか？
You can see this from the distribution of rainfall
降水量分布を見ればわかる
That is to say, it lasts for two or three days.
つまり、２～３日は続くということです。
Rainfall is very heavy
雨が非常に激しいです
There are even many times when the rainfall per hour is close to 100 mm
時間雨量が100ミリ近くになることも多いです。
That's 10 centimeters, 10 centimeters per hour.
それは10センチメートル、1時間あたり10センチメートルです。
That went on for hours or more
それは何時間以上も続きました
Well of course it brings it up on the hill for this some
まあ、もちろん、このために丘の上にそれをもたらします
Our mountain, this oxygen-rich soil
私たちの山、酸素豊富なこの土
The capacity of oxygen-containing water is already saturated
酸素を含む水の容量はすでに飽和しています
So causing that excess pressure on the soil
土壌に過剰な圧力がかかるため、
In the end, the whole thing is a landslide or avalanche.
結局のところ、すべてが土砂崩れか雪崩になります。
This massive avalanche of avalanche
この大規模な雪崩
Let this unfortunate disaster money
この不幸な災害にお金を与えてください
This is a still
これは静止画です
It should be a village with a very good environment
とても環境の良い村のはずです
Later, Xiaolian Village became like this
その後、小蓮村はこうなりました
that's a big loss
それは大きな損失です
It means heavy rainfall
大雨ということは
But there is another type of rain
しかし、別の種類の雨もあります
when the typhoon comes
台風が来ると
is the total rainfall
総降水量です
But it rained a lot in a short time
しかし、短時間にかなりの雨が降りました
It rained an average of 600mm in 6 hours
6時間で平均600mmの雨が降りました
About 60 cm of rain
雨量約60センチ
within 6 hours
6時間以内
Then our general drainage system cannot cope with this kind of
そうすると、私たちの一般的な排水システムではこの種の処理には対応できません。
so-called very rapid heavy rainfall in a short period of time
いわゆる短期間に降る非常に急速な大雨
Then this will also cause a flooding event.
そうなると、これも洪水現象を引き起こすことになります。
If this kind of rain falls in Taipei City
台北市にこんな雨が降ったら
No matter how good the water pump in Taipei City is
台北市の給水ポンプがどんなに優れていても
Maybe it's too late
もしかしたらもう手遅れかもしれない
so it's a very challenging
とても挑戦的です
that is
あれは
That is to say, we now have some rainfall patterns that are very violent.
つまり、現在、非常に激しい降雨パターンがいくつか存在しています。
Brings a lot of rain in a short time
短時間に大量の雨が降る
Look at this example also happened two years ago
この例も2年前に起こりました
A case you may be familiar with
あなたがよく知っているかもしれないケース
typhoon leki
台風レキ
Please raise your hand if you are impressed
感動した方は手を挙げてください
Do you remember if you noticed that
それに気づいたか覚えていますか
At the beginning, the news mentioned the Suhua Highway
ニュースの冒頭で蘇花公路について触れていました
Unfortunately, two tour buses just fell down
残念ながら観光バス2台が転落してしまいました
It was this unfortunate accident that washed into the Pacific Ocean.
太平洋に流されたこの不幸な事故でした。
In this example the same means
この例では同じ意味です
it's four hours in a very short time
4時間って本当にあっという間ですね
More than 100mm of rain falls every hour
1時間に100mm以上の雨が降る
under this amount of rain
この量の雨の中では
also caused a lot of collapse
多くの崩壊も引き起こした
There are some areas like these areas around Suao
蘇澳周辺にはこのようなエリアがいくつかあります
The problem of its rainfall causing disasters has been highlighted
降雨による災害の問題がクローズアップされている
Then this event we are in
それから私たちが参加しているこのイベント
Now is the time for the government to regulate the impact of this torrential rain on us
今こそ政府がこの豪雨による私たちへの影響を規制すべき時です
It also includes the control of traffic.
交通規制も含まれます。
Especially on this kind of rough road
特にこういう悪路では
When the rainfall reaches a certain level
雨量が一定量に達すると
its road is closed
その道は閉鎖されています
to avoid this unfortunate situation
この不幸な状況を避けるために
simply speaking
簡単に言えば
I put my part about typhoons and disasters today
今日は台風と災害について載せます
a simple section
簡単なセクション
report here
ここに報告してください
We probably understand that
おそらく私たちはそれを理解しています
our nature
私たちの性質
Taiwan is in such an environment
台湾はそういう環境にある
Typhoon is a risk of self-disaster
台風は自災の危険がある
These risks are of course mainly related to rainfall
もちろん、これらのリスクは主に降雨に関連しています
Of course there are other conditions including address
もちろん住所など他の条件もございます
But we also noticed
しかし、私たちも気づいたのです
The larger problem of the whole society
社会全体のより大きな問題
includes social change
社会変化も含まれる
population because we have a large population
人口が多いので
and concentrated
そして集中した
because of land use
土地利用のせいで
Factors such as land development
土地開発などの要因
lower limit of stratum etc.
階層の下限など
Let this natural original risk factor
この自然本来の危険因子を
more improvement
さらなる改善
what's more
そのうえ
may be this is a very large one
これは非常に大きいものかもしれません
A very important issue in the current scientific community
現在の科学界における非常に重要な問題
the whole change of climate
気候全体の変化
That might also bring some new shocks
それはまた新たな衝撃をもたらすかもしれない
This impact includes the global
この影響には世界規模のものも含まれます
What we call the issue of warming
私たちが温暖化問題と呼ぶもの
This issue may also cause
この問題により、次のような問題が発生する可能性もあります
part of the typhoon
台風の一部
or the torrential rain it brings
あるいはそれがもたらす豪雨
its increased strength
その増大した強さ
These changes may make
これらの変更により、
The risks we face are greater
私たちが直面するリスクはさらに大きくなります
In particular, various disasters will also load
特に様々な災害も搭載されます
Those neutralizing effects
それらの中和効果
Let's pave in the higher
もっと高く舗装しましょう
The environmental risks of these so-called disasters
これらのいわゆる災害による環境リスク
then have to face this problem
それからこの問題に直面しなければなりません
That's the whole world now
それが今の世界のすべてだ
Not just one that we all pay attention to in Taiwan
台湾で私たちが注目しているのはそれだけではありません
combined with natural science
自然科学と組み合わせる
Plus socioeconomic and so on
さらに社会経済など
a major issue
大きな問題
Then I think everyone today
それから、今日は皆さんもそう思います
Coming here must also be very concerned about this issue.
ここに来る人もこの問題を非常に心配しているはずです。
Well, I just had the chance to meet a few people today.
さて、今日は何人かの方にお会いする機会がありました。
It happened to be a colleague of the Central Plains Academy
たまたまセントラルプレーンズアカデミーの同僚だった
The Central Plains Academy also attaches great importance to this issue
セントラルプレーンズアカデミーもこの問題を非常に重視しています
There is also a research center called the Environmental Change Research Center
環境変動研究センターという研究センターもあります。
One of the key issues is also very related to this
重要な問題の 1 つはこれにも非常に関連しています
Now the Central Plains Institute is still promoting a
現在もセントラルプレーンズ研究所は、
with this our worldwide international organization
私たちの世界的な国際組織とともに
What about a combined unit?
合体ユニットはどうなるの？
It is called IRDR
それはIRDRと呼ばれます
It is an internationally relevant one
国際的にも通用する内容です
a research center related to the so-called method of disaster research
いわゆる災害研究手法に関する研究センター
there is an office
オフィスがあります
The office is located in Zhongyuanyuan
オフィスは中源源にあります
That's the former Liu Zhaohe and the vice president of our Central Plains Academy
それは元劉昭和であり、私たちのセントラルプレーンズアカデミーの副学長です
leading this team
このチームを率いる
i think it's a big issue
それは大きな問題だと思う
still in progress
まだ進行中
I think if there is
あればと思います
Especially young friends who are interested, etc.
特に興味のある若い友達など。
I think there will be opportunities in the future
今後もチャンスはあると思います
Participate in research work related to these
これらに関連する研究活動に参加する
then i'll start now
それでは今から始めます
typhoon itself
台風そのもの
Then to introduce the typhoon, I will use this picture to start
それでは台風の紹介ですが、まずはこの写真から始めます
In fact if
実際に
Of course, few of you here may have the opportunity to say that during a typhoon
もちろん、ここにいる皆さんの中には、台風のときにそんなことを言える機会がある人は少ないかもしれません。
I really went inside the typhoon and flew inside to see the typhoon
本当に台風の中に行って、台風を見るために中に飛んできた
If there is such an experience like this one
こんな経験があったら
in the eye of the typhoon
台風の目の中で
This photo was taken while flying at an altitude of about 3,000 meters
この写真は高度約3,000メートルを飛行中に撮影されました。
What you see is actually very beautiful
あなたが見ているものは実際とても美しいです
of course we are
もちろん私たちはです
say he
彼は言う
From a scientific point of view, he is really a beauty
科学的な観点から見ると、彼は本当に美しいです
I say it's a beauty but of course he's also a beast
美人って言うけど、もちろん野獣でもあるよ
that this
これは
this one
これです
such a natural
とても自然な
what about him
彼についてはどうですか
Topics with lots of interesting science
興味深い科学がたくさんあるトピック
our nature
私たちの性質
Logically speaking
論理的に言えば
Why did he produce such a
なぜ彼はそのようなものを生み出したのか
Where's the giant beast monster?
巨大な獣のモンスターはどこですか？
Why is the normal wind speed ranging from a few meters to 10 meters per second?
通常の風速が毎秒数メートルから 10 メートルの範囲であるのはなぜですか?
Why does it have such an unstable
なんでこんなに不安定になるんだろう
it will keep increasing
それは増え続けるだろう
In the end, every year in different corners of some seas around the world
結局のところ、毎年、世界中のいくつかの海のさまざまな場所で
would grow huge so-called storms
いわゆる嵐が巨大化するだろう
And when it spins, there's no way to stop it
そしてそれが回転すると、それを止める方法はありません
The fastest possible wind speed can be as high as 60-70 meters per second
最も速い風速は毎秒60〜70メートルに達することもあります
That's basically destroying a lot of
それは基本的に多くのものを破壊することです
these our trees and more
これらの私たちの木など
then it's raining
それから雨が降っています
Just like the introduction just now, there are a lot of heavy rain
先ほどのご紹介のように、大雨が多いです
That's actually a very interesting scientific question
それは実際には非常に興味深い科学的質問です
And when I just ate
そしてちょうど食べたところ
During the meal, I happened to chat with a colleague
食事中、たまたま同僚と話をしていました
In fact, what about this phenomenon?
実際、この現象はどうなのでしょうか？
how did it come about
それはどのようにして起こったのか
how long can it last
どれくらい続くでしょうか
how it moves
どのように動くか
why its strength increases
なぜ強度が上がるのか
Then how strong can it be enhanced to the limit?
では限界までどこまで強化できるのでしょうか？
how much rain can it rain
どのくらいの雨が降ることができますか
Every scientific question is still being explored by many scientists
あらゆる科学的疑問は今も多くの科学者によって研究されています
Of course it took many years of hard work
もちろん長年の努力が必要だった
In fact, we understand more and more about these
実際、私たちはこれらについてますます理解しています
Then of course I will share some interesting parts with you today.
もちろん、今日は興味深い部分をいくつか共有します。
Another thing to mention is that
もう一つ言及すべきことは、
What about the depth of the typhoon?
台風の深さはどうなるのでしょうか？
The most special place is that it can only be found on the sea
最も特別な場所は海の上でしか見られないことです
Only in warm enough oceans
十分に暖かい海でのみ
Then it has a very close interaction with the ocean
そして海と非常に密接な相互作用を持っています
The interaction with the ocean itself
海そのものとの関わり
Another very interesting natural science question
もう一つの非常に興味深い自然科学の質問
That is, two fluids with different qualities
つまり、性質の異なる 2 つの流体
air atmosphere and ocean
大気と海洋
a very low density atmosphere
非常に低密度の大気
a dense ocean
濃い海
how they go to each other how the wind blows the ocean
彼らはどのようにお互いに行きますか 風が海をどのように吹きますか
How the ocean affects the activity of the atmosphere through the exchange of heat
海洋が熱交換を通じて大気の活動にどのような影響を与えるか
that's a very important issue
それはとても重要な問題です
That's inside our typhoon
それは私たちの台風の中です
is a very fast atmosphere-ocean interaction
大気と海洋の相互作用は非常に速いです
Then everyone in this movie after tomorrow
それでは皆さん、明日以降この映画に出演してください
What we see is also the interaction of the atmosphere and the ocean.
私たちが見ているのは、大気と海の相互作用でもあります。
But that effect is a longer-term change
しかし、その影響は長期的な変化です
One of our oceans may be longer
私たちの海の一つはもっと長いかもしれない
Changes in ocean currents from centuries to millennia
数世紀から数千年にわたる海流の変化
How to change our climate system
気候システムを変えるには
that's a very fundamental one
それはとても基本的なことです
fun big one physical
楽しい大きなフィジカル
or natural science issues
または自然科学の問題
Well, I can’t give you a detailed introduction to the typhoon itself.
そうですね、台風そのものについて詳しく紹介することはできません。
But I'll drop by and talk to you guys
でも、立ち寄って皆さんとお話しします
It shouldn't be called promotion
それを昇進と呼ぶべきではない
should introduce
導入すべき
This one was just a few years ago
これはほんの数年前の話です
The book that I am involved in translating
私が翻訳に携わった本
This book is called
この本はと呼ばれます
The Vine Wing is talking about the typhoon
Vine Wing が台風について話しています
That's called a giant wind in America
それはアメリカでは巨大な風と呼ばれています
the original author of the book
この本の原作者
It happens to be my supervisor abroad
たまたま海外の私の上司です
Then he is a master researcher in this field
それで彼はこの分野のマスター研究者です
the master
的大師
That's also a member of the National Academy of Sciences
それは米国科学アカデミーの会員でもあります
That's because my teacher published a book
先生が本を出版したからです
It is a very good science book
とても良い科学の本です
I spent a year and a half a few years ago
数年前に1年半過ごしました
just translate it into Chinese
それを中国語に翻訳するだけです
right here
ここにあります
so come prepared
だから準備して来てください
If you want to have a deeper understanding of typhoons,
台風についてもっと深く知りたいなら
in fact the book
実はその本
It may also provide you with many useful ideas
役立つアイデアもたくさん得られるかもしれません
Then I will give this book to Mr. Peng first.
それでは、私はまずこの本を彭さんに渡します。
Maybe you can pass it on
もしかしたら引き継いでもらえるかもしれない
no intention of quitting school
学校を辞めるつもりはない
Every library can find it
どの図書館でも見つけることができます
Then what do I think the characteristics of this book are?
では、この本の特徴は何だと思いますか？
What about the typhoon it introduced?
それがもたらした台風はどうなったのでしょうか？
In fact there are scientific issues
実は科学的な問題もある
So our topic today starts from this
それでは今日の話題はここから始まります
I put the inspiration for translating this book
この本を翻訳するにあたってインスピレーションを与えました
it has many scientific issues
多くの科学的問題を抱えている
But it is also mixed with a lot of humanities
しかし、それはまた多くの人文科学と混合されています
historical and artistic
歴史的かつ芸術的
so i think it's very interesting
だからとても面白いと思います
It's worth it when you have time
時間があるときに利用する価値があります
can read
読める
as if i just mentioned here
あたかも私がちょうどここで言及したかのように
The topic of our speech today
今日のスピーチのテーマ
it has a typhoon with a historical view
歴史を感じさせる台風がある
typhoon with scientific dimension
科学的側面を持つ台風
even literary level
文学レベルでも
I hope this book can give you a
この本があなたに何かを与えることができれば幸いです
more complete different aspects
より完全なさまざまな側面
this is a scientific question
これは科学的な質問です
can i quote today
今日引用してもいいですか
In fact, our domestic
実は我が家の
I saw it in today's early starters
今日のアーリースターターで見ました
Mr. Zhu, are you here today?
朱さん、今日は来ていますか？
Are you in the Humanities or History Institute?
あなたは人文科学研究所または歴史研究所に所属していますか?
Mr. Zhu Malone
朱馬龍先生
Today is good
今日はいいですね
i saw his name
彼の名前を見ました
in Taiwan University
台湾大学で
a few years ago about ten years ago
数年前 約10年前
I have read a history department
歴史部門を読みました
student research essay
学生の研究エッセイ
Just researching how the typhoon got its name
台風の名前の由来を調べてみました
did very very detailed
とてもとても詳しくやった
analysis of research
研究の分析
In the book I introduced today
今日紹介した本の中で
He also has a question about how the typhoon came
彼は台風がどうやって来たのかについても質問している
There are some analyzes on how the hurricanes in the United States come from
米国のハリケーンがどのようにして発生するかについては、いくつかの分析があります。
what about in cuba
キューバではどうですか
they were in the caribbean a long time ago
彼らは昔カリブ海にいました
I knew there was such a phenomenon as a hurricane.
ハリケーンのような現象があることは知っていました。
In fact they have some mythical stories
実際、彼らにはいくつかの神話的な物語があります
to describe the source of these storms
これらの嵐の原因を説明するために
In fact this of our hurricane
実際、これは私たちのハリケーンのことです
What about the word Hurricane?
ハリケーンという言葉はどうでしょうか？
In fact, it's from these guys over there
実際、それは向こうの人たちからのものです
including from their Inca culture
彼らのインカ文化からのものも含めて
All the way to the culture of the Caribbean
カリブ海の文化まで
there is such wisdom
そんな知恵があるんだ
to describe this horrible god of evil
この恐ろしい悪の神を説明するには
Then there is such a stone totem
そうすると、こんな石のトーテムがあるんです
They were all found out later
それらはすべて後で判明しました
that they think they
彼らは自分たちだと思っていると
This is the storm god they saw
これが彼らが見た嵐の神です
It's amazing what people of later generations are thinking about saying
後世の人が考えていることってすごいですね
The typhoon they drew at the beginning rotated
最初に描いた台風が回転した
The direction of the shaft back is already correct.
シャフトバックの向きはすでに合っています。
Is it a coincidence?
偶然ですか？
Or are they already available from this one
それとも、すでにここから利用可能ですか
The direction of this number of five texts that was blown down
吹き飛ばされた5つのテキストのこの数の方向
But the characteristic that the wind is rotating counterclockwise in the whole northern hemisphere
ただし、北半球全体では風が反時計回りに回転しているという特徴があります。
Then the typhoon symbol in the scientific world of our modern standard is consistent with this, and it is drawn like this
すると、現代の科学の世界における台風のシンボルはこれと一致しており、次のように描かれます。
Another very interesting story related to our East is
私たちの東洋に関連したもう一つの非常に興味深い話は、
In fact, these storms are also changing history
実際、これらの嵐は歴史を変えつつあります
In 1274 AD, it was in Lake Bilie, and at that time the Mongols were considered their kings or emperors
西暦1274年、それはビリエ湖にありました。つまり、当時、モンゴル人は彼らの王または皇帝とみなされていました。
After he has unified the entire country of China
中国全土を統一した後、
His ambition gradually shifted to wanting to continue to conquer other countries including Japan
彼の野心は徐々に、日本を含む他の国を征服し続けたいというものに変わりました。
So in 1274, this Hu Bilie sent his army to combine with the conquered Korea at that time
そこで1274年、この胡丞烈は当時征服された朝鮮と連合するために軍隊を派遣した。
There is a joint army composed of the Han army, Mongolian army and North Korea
漢軍、モンゴル軍、北朝鮮軍からなる連合軍がある
an army of one hundred thousand
十万の軍隊
At that time, it was already an incredible army
あの時すでにすごい軍隊だった
Attack Japan with thousands of these warships
数千隻の軍艦で日本を攻撃する
Then they go directly to the Kyushu area, of course the first line
それから九州方面へ直行、もちろん第一線
What about this ship? It's almost a success.
この船はどうですか? ほぼ成功です。
They all beat Japan
全員が日本に勝った
The Japanese are losing ground
日本人は立場を失いつつある
That's because the Mongolian army didn't dare to enter too quickly
それはモンゴル軍があまり早く進入する勇気がなかったからです。
So most of the troops stay on the ship
そのため、ほとんどの軍隊は船に残っています
The result is at this time
現時点での結果は
They encountered a miraculous cleansing of a typhoon
彼らは奇跡的な台風の浄化に遭遇した
completely annihilated
完全に全滅した
The Japanese put this one
日本人がこれを置いた
What about the history of this one?
これの歴史についてはどうですか？
this one that caused this one
これがこれを引き起こしたもの
become a giant wind
巨大な風になる
The original meaning of Kamikaze Nahara in Japan is called
日本におけるカミカゼナハラの本来の意味は、
Kamakaze means Kamikaze
カマカゼとは神風という意味です
In 1281, the same history repeated itself
1281年、同じ歴史が繰り返された
Later, the original army was attacking Japan
その後、元の軍隊は日本を攻撃していました
But in the same situation
でも同じ状況で
What about this period of history in Japan?
日本の歴史のこの時期はどうなるのでしょうか？
There are very detailed records in Japanese books
日本の本には非常に詳細な記録がある
in 1281
1281年に
There is a professor at Merchant Marine University in Tokyo, Japan
東京の商船大学に教授がいます
he based on these histories
彼はこれらの歴史に基づいて
with modern technology
現代のテクノロジーを使って
Sheng Na and so on
シェンナなど
To this open sea of ​​Kyushu
九州のこの大海へ
Yin Island and so on, some Yin Yin Yin Yin
陰島など、いくつかの陰陰陰陰
the vicinity of these islands
これらの島の近く
To do some biological exploration of the seabed
海底の生物学的調査を行うため
Including later this unprecedented one
この前例のないものを後で含めます
vehicle down detection
車両ダウン検知
I found many of these
私はこれらをたくさん見つけました
At the beginning, this Mongolia or reinforcements
冒頭、このモンゴルか援軍
what they left behind
彼らが残したもの
Weapons and some property, etc.
武器や財産など
That also indirectly confirms this period of history
それはまた、この期間の歴史を間接的に裏付けるものです
So this typhoon also changed history
この台風も歴史を変えたということですね
Without these two or several
これら 2 つまたはいくつかがなければ
The impact of the magical typhoon
マジカル台風の影響
Maybe Japan has changed
日本は変わってしまったのかもしれない
I don't know what it's like now
今はどうなっているのか分かりません
History
歴史
What about the development?
開発についてはどうですか？
that in this one
この中のそれ
this hair
この髪
this of course
これはもちろん
What about this kamikaze?
カミカゼはどこですか？
By the time of World War II
第二次世界大戦の頃までに
This term is of course inspired by Japan
この用語はもちろん日本からインスピレーションを得たものです
to some extent as
ある程度としては
a metaphor for them
彼らの比喩
as a symbol of their patriotism
彼らの愛国心の象徴として
unfortunately
不幸にも
organized the so-called kamikaze
いわゆるカミカゼを組織した
come from the same noun
同じ名詞から来ています
that's unfortunate of course
それはもちろん残念なことだ
Many young people were patriotic
多くの若者は愛国的だった
sacrificed their lives
彼らの命を犠牲にした
So the word kamikaze
だからカミカゼという言葉は
Later it was tantamount to being misused
後にそれは悪用されたに等しい
or to be quoted
または引用される
In World War II became
第二次世界大戦ではこうなった
symbol of kamikaze
神風の象徴
when i was raw
私が生だったとき
Indeed there is such a
確かにそのようなことはあります
Nature's arrangement just protects
自然の摂理がただ守ってくれる
Japan at that time
当時の日本
well here is a brief history
さて、ここで簡単な歴史をご紹介します
An introduction to typhoons
台風の紹介
Then I introduced it in the nutrition section.
続いて栄養のコーナーで紹介させていただきました。
the poem of the poem
詩の詩
Of course three to four to one
もちろん3対4対1
He may not have personally met the so-called Hurricane
彼はいわゆるハリケーンに直接会ったことはないかもしれない
when i dined like today
今日のように食事をしたとき
Teacher Liang, a colleague asked me
リャン先生、同僚が私に尋ねました。
Why there are no typhoons in Europe
なぜヨーロッパには台風がないのか
Then of course I can add more to you later.
もちろん、後でさらに追加することもできます。
Basically the only place where a typhoon has a chance to form
基本的に台風が発生する可能性がある唯一の場所
in the warmer waters of the tropics
暖かい熱帯の海で
So whether in the Atlantic or the Pacific
つまり、大西洋であろうと太平洋であろうと
After these hurricanes formed
これらのハリケーンが発生した後、
Just in these tropical regions are in the so-called envelope belt
ちょうどこれらの熱帯地域は、いわゆる包囲帯にあります
Take him in Dongfeng and move west
彼を東風に連れて西へ移動する
So he has no chance to go north
だから彼には北に行く機会がない
Or go northeast to Europe
あるいは北東のヨーロッパへ行くか
So there is no typhoon in Europe
だからヨーロッパには台風はない
So Shakespeare itself certainly didn't
つまり、シェイクスピア自体は確かにそうではなかった
Experienced a real Hurricane
本物のハリケーンを体験しました
But in this UK or off the coast of Europe
でも、このイギリスやヨーロッパ沖では
It could also be that there are a lot of storms
暴風雨が多いことも考えられます
these may be winter storms
これらは冬の嵐かもしれない
not a summer storm
夏の嵐ではない
the more different its physical properties
物理的性質が異なるほど
Written in these famous classics of their history
彼らの歴史のこれらの有名な古典に書かれています
They also take this so-called power of nature
彼らはまた、このいわゆる自然の力を利用します
This horrific situation with this torrential rain force
この豪雨勢力によるこの悲惨な状況
described very very vividly
とてもとても生き生きと説明されています
If you are interested, you can read the Chinese and English parts separately.
興味があれば中国語と英語の部分を分けて読んでみてください。
Or the Chinese part we translated
または私たちが翻訳した中国語の部分
trying to experience
経験しようとしている
Then today I will probably do a very simple one.
それから今日はおそらく非常に単純なものをやることになります。
an introduction
紹介
what about this end of america
アメリカのこの端はどうですか
That's another famous poet I also visited
それから、これも私が訪れた別の有名な詩人です
he commemorates him
彼は彼を追悼する
The place where he was born because he is in Ma Chau
馬洲にいるので彼が生まれた場所
Then this one Emily Dickinson wrote this song
そして、エミリー・ディキンソンがこの曲を書きました
This poem is also very beautiful and talks about the wind and rain
この詩もとても美しく、風と雨について語っています。
water etc.
水など
I just happen to
たまたま
After this translation, I cooperated with one of my juniors last year and now it has become a song
この翻訳の後、私は昨年学校の女子生徒の一人と協力し、今では歌になりました。
Maybe those who are interested, I can broadcast it to everyone in the future
興味のある方は、今後、皆さんに放送できるかもしれません
Ok, let's go back to Typhoon
さて、台風の話に戻りましょう
We are influencing what is going to happen in our Taiwan today
私たちは今日台湾で起こることに影響を与えています
What about the Sura typhoon we just talked about?
先ほど話したスーラ台風はどうでしょうか？
Some newspapers you may have heard say
あなたが聞いたことがある新聞もあるでしょう。
Everyone is worrying about it's so-called dot
いわゆるドットのことでみんなが悩んでる
Possibly a Northwest station
おそらく北西部の駅
If you notice the news
そのニュースに気づいたら
You may have heard the term
という言葉を聞いたことがあるかもしれません
Let me explain to you what Northwest TV is doing.
ノースウェストテレビが何をしているのか説明しましょう。
In 1996, there was a typhoon cleaning Taiwan called Hebo Typhoon
1996年、ヘボ台風と呼ばれる台湾を襲う台風がありました。
If anyone here has any impression, please raise your hand
ここで何か感想のある方は手を挙げてください
Not bad, it seems that everyone is also deeply affected by it
悪くない、みんなもかなりの影響を受けているようだ
This typhoon landed in Keelung from the northern part of Taiwan and then left Taiwan.
この台風は台湾北部から基隆に上陸し、その後台湾を離れました。
But what?
でも何？
It was the strongest typhoon in those years
当時最強の台風だった
that's what we're doing
それが私たちがここにいる理由です
On the Taipei Line, there is another mine stall on the top of Wufen Mountain in New Taipei City.
台北線の新北市五分山の頂上にももう一つの鉱山露店があります。
The original scene
オリジナルのシーン
This radar is very telling
このレーダーは非常に優れています
because the whole radar
なぜならレーダー全体が
The so-called modern radar
いわゆる現代のレーダー
Setup in Taiwan
台湾でのセットアップ
this is the first
これが最初です
is the highest technology
最高の技術です
The modern one is called Duppler's
現代のものはダップラーと呼ばれます
new radar
新しいレーダー
it can detect
それは検出できます
distribution of rainfall
降水量の分布
and typhoon wind
そして台風の風
indirect estimate
間接推定
Doppler effect
ドップラー効果
wind speed can be estimated
風速が推定できる
This radar in 1996's
1996年のこのレーダー
Set on July 23
7月23日に設定
original design
オリジナルデザイン
It can tolerate winds of 65 meters per second
毎秒65メートルの風にも耐えられる
it is well designed
うまく設計されています
only a week
たった一週間
July 30-31, 1996
1996 年 7 月 30 ～ 31 日
Typhoon Herb directly
タイフーンハーブ直接
center passes nearby
センターが近くを通ります
The result is very accurate
結果は非常に正確です
This typhoon is as high as every second
この台風は毎秒の高さです
70 meters
70メートル
very precise
非常に正確な
This radar is destroyed
このレーダーは破壊されました
this is also
これもまた
karma
カルマ
Our Nature Benefits
私たちの自然の恩恵
like know what we're doing detection
私たちが何をしているかを知っているような検出
Of course it took another year to rebuild
その後、もちろん再構築にはさらに1年かかりました
well that's an interesting story
まあ、それは興味深い話ですね
But the point of this typhoon is that this typhoon passes by like this
でも、この台風のポイントは、この台風がこうやって通り過ぎていくということです。
The wind of the typhoon revolves counterclockwise
台風の風は反時計回りに回る
So in Taiwan when he was close to Taiwan and still here
それで、彼が台湾に近かったとき、そして今もここにいるときの台湾で
The place where Taiwan's fresh water exits is blowing
台湾の清水の出る場所が吹いている
probably northerly to northwesterly
おそらく北から北西
So he will block the flooding of our freshwater river
それで彼は私たちの淡水川の氾濫を止めてくれるでしょう
The Danshui River is collected from the Xindian Creek Keelung River
淡水河は基隆河の新店渓から採取されます。
The only exit with the Great Khan Creek
グレートカーンクリークへの唯一の出口
So his whole water is accumulated
それで彼の水は全部溜まる
and then add the metropolitan area rainfall
そこに首都圏の降雨量を加えます
so the whole place is flooded
だからその場所全体が水浸しになる
so in taipei
それで台北で
For example, the setting island in Taipei City, etc.
例えば台北市の舞台となる島など。
Both sides of this West River are completely flooded
このウェスト川の両岸は完全に氾濫しています
very severe flooding
非常に激しい洪水
Then this situation becomes Northwest TV
そうなると、この状況はノースウェストテレビになります
So Northwest TV should refer to
したがって、ノースウェストテレビは次のように言及する必要があります
Only typhoons pass by here to bring this water
ここを通過するのは台風だけがこの水を運んでくる
When the northwest wind blows in the northwest corner of Taiwan
台湾の北西部に北西風が吹くとき
this typhoon
この台風
Then this kind of typhoon will easily cause relatively severe disasters in our Taipei county and city
この種の台風は、私たちの台北県と市に比較的大きな災害を引き起こしやすいでしょう。
Our typhoon this time is coming from here
今回の台風はここから来ます
But it may slowly turn around like this
でもこのままゆっくり好転するかもしれない
So have features like
したがって、次のような機能があります
So we need to be more cautious in our northern places
したがって、北部の地域ではさらに注意する必要があります
Well, this is called Xibeitan
さて、これは西北潭と呼ばれるものです
then i won't repeat it
それなら繰り返さないよ
I will introduce a few terms to you today
今日はいくつかの用語を紹介します
Another one that everyone still remembers is Typhoon Nali 10 years ago in 2001
誰もが今でも覚えているもう一つの台風は、10年前の2001年のナリ台風です。
What is special about this typhoon is
今回の台風の特徴は、
it's already in september
もう9月ですね
At this time, the sea temperature is already relatively low.
この時点ではすでに海水温は比較的低いです。
It stands to reason that typhoons are less likely to stay in the same place for too long
台風が同じ場所に長く留まる可能性が低いのは当然です
But it brushed down from the northeast with a very peculiar trajectory
しかし、それは非常に奇妙な軌道で北東から吹き下ろしました
Took 49 hours to pass through Taiwan
台湾を49時間かけて過ごした
very slow
非常に遅い
that would cause a lot of accumulated rainfall
それは大量の降雨を引き起こすでしょう
because it moved for a long time
長時間移動していたので
raining
雨が降っている
It rains all the time, but the ocean continuously provides water vapor for the typhoon to turn into rainfall
雨はずっと降り続いていますが、海は台風が雨に変わるために水蒸気を供給し続けています。
So we have a lot of rain here, especially in the metropolitan Taipei area
そのため、ここ、特に台北都市圏では雨がたくさん降ります。
You all know that it caused a serious incident at that time.
当時大変な事件を引き起こしたことは皆さんもご存じでしょう。
Situation of stagnant water
滞留水の状況
Let me tell you about another type of typhoon called Morakot.
モラコットと呼ばれる別の種類の台風についてお話しましょう。
this typhoon
この台風
happened three years ago
3年前の出来事
He himself caused the so-called baba flood
彼自身がいわゆるババ洪水を引き起こした
His wind is not very strong
彼の風はあまり強くない
He's just a basic moderate typhoon
彼はただの基本的な中程度の台風です
But he moved very slowly before he passed Taiwan
しかし、台湾を通過する前に彼は非常にゆっくりと動きました
plus
プラス
what about this season
今シーズンはどうですか
He is in early August, July to August
彼は8月上旬、7月から8月にいます
We happen to be in the whole of Asia
私たちはたまたまアジア全体にいます
When the southwest monsoon prevails and intensifies
南西モンスーンが優勢になり、強まるとき
What about this strong monsoon?
この強いモンスーンはどうでしょうか？
This place in the South China Sea is very humid and warm air brings up
南シナ海のこの場所は非常に湿気が多く、暖かい空気が湧き出ています。
Although the typhoon is
台風ですが、
On the east side of Taiwan, the warm and humid air brought up by the southwest airflow
台湾の東側では、南西気流によって暖かく湿った空気が運ばれます。
Will be affected by typhoon and terrain
台風や地形の影響を受ける
will cause a lot of rain in the southwestern part of Taiwan
台湾南西部では大雨が降るでしょう
When this pattern and this form appear
この模様、この形が出てきたら
In the southwest but not in the center of the typhoon
南西にありますが、台風の中心ではありません
while in the southwestern plains and mountainous areas there is a lot of rainfall
一方、南西部の平野部や山岳地帯では降水量が多くなります。
That caused a very serious so-called bus storm disaster
それは非常に深刻ないわゆるバス嵐災害を引き起こしました
Morakot's Storm has another feature
モラコットの嵐にはもう一つの特徴があります
It's the role of the southwest airflow that I just mentioned.
それが先ほど言った南西気流の役割です。
From now on, we now understand everyone's understanding of the entire typhoon prevention
今後、台風対策全体について皆様のご理解が深まりました
it's a little more complicated
それはもう少し複雑です
In addition to considering the changes in the wind and rain of the typhoon itself
台風そのものの風雨の変化も考慮する
Also consider our larger scope
より広い範囲についても考慮してください
The role of the incoming southwesterly gusts over hundreds of kilometers
数百キロメートルにわたって到来する南西の突風の役割
When the airflow is strong
風量が強いとき
is possible
可能だ
may have additional effects
追加の効果がある可能性があります
Of course, the impact will be more serious in the southwestern part of Taiwan.
もちろん、台湾南西部では影響がより深刻になるだろう。
Another thing to mention here is that
ここでもう一つ言及しておきたいのは、
What about this particular case of our Morakot?
私たちのモラコットのこの特定のケースについてはどうですか?
let's take a look
見てみましょう
This is the storage capacity of two reservoirs in southwestern Taiwan
これは台湾南西部にある 2 つの貯水池の貯水容量です
They are Wushantou Reservoir and Zhenwen Reservoir respectively.
それぞれ烏山頭水庫と鎮文水庫です。
The two reservoirs were counted from January 2009
2 つの貯水池は 2009 年 1 月からカウントされました
Everyone sees that the water is getting less and less
誰もが水がどんどん少なくなっているのを見てます
Because there was very little rain in the whole spring that year.
なぜなら、その年の春はずっと雨がほとんど降らなかったからです。
So getting dry is its benefit
乾燥するのが利点です
By June and July of that year, the water volume had reached
同年6月から7月までに水量は
Compared with the so-called water shortage situation
いわゆる水不足の状況に比べて
But a typhoon came on August 8
しかし、8月8日に台風が来ました。
dramatic increase in water
水の劇的な増加
Just because of the cleaning of Typhoon Morakot
台風モラコットの影響で
Then what
じゃあ何
excess water
超水量
But what about after the water caused the flood?
しかし、水が洪水を引き起こした後はどうでしょうか。
It quickly lost to the sea again
またすぐに海に負けてしまった
So the reservoir can't hold so much water
そのため、貯水池にはそれほど多くの水を蓄えることができません
So then suddenly the drought came next door
それで突然干ばつが隣にやって来た
Every other year until another new typhoon comes
新たな台風が来るまで隔年
There is water in the reservoir
貯水池には水が溜まっている
So the arrangement of our reservoir in Taiwan
台湾の貯水池の配置
In fact, it has a lot to do with how to grasp the dynamics of the typhoon
実は、それは台風のダイナミクスをどう捉えるかに大きく関係しています。
The reservoir wants to keep the water a little more
貯水池はもう少し水を貯めておきたい
But I'm afraid it will burst again
でもまた爆発しそうで怖い
If it drains water when the typhoon is strongest
台風が最も強いときに水を抜くと
The disaster will be more serious
災害はさらに深刻になるだろう
So this is a very big learning
これは非常に大きな学びです
This is why we in Taiwan are suffering from this drought
これが私たち台湾がこの干ばつに苦しんでいる理由です
Alternate process of water shortage or flood
水不足または洪水の代替プロセス
Part of the reason it's very difficult
それが非常に難しい理由の一つは
I just mentioned that typhoon Morakot will cause such a large amount of precipitation
台風モラコットがこれほど大量の降水量を引き起こすと先ほど言いました
partly caused by accumulated precipitation
部分的には蓄積された降水が原因
because it moves very slowly as it passes
通過するときの動きが非常に遅いため
In a slow process, it can continue to rain
プロセスが遅いため、雨が降り続ける可能性があります
It's been a long time
おひさしぶりですね
This process is also closely related to the topography of Taiwan.
このプロセスは台湾の地形とも密接に関係しています。
Main file of Taiwan terrain
台湾地形のメインファイル
You can imagine our terrain itself
私たちの地形そのものを想像してみてください
about three kilometers high
高さ約3キロメートル
There are even places close to four kilometers
4キロ近いところもある
Under the main file of this high mountain in Taiwan
台湾のこの高山のメインファイルの下で
Although the development of the vertical airflow of the typhoon itself
台風自体の垂直気流が発達しているものの、
range of rotation possible
回転可能範囲
up to a height of ten kilometers
高さ10キロメートルまで
But its strongest part is within a few kilometers of the lower floors
しかし、その最も強力な部分は低層階から数キロメートル以内にあります
I just received a word from Shan’s main file at this place
この場所でシャンのメインファイルから一言を受け取りました
the airflow will change
空気の流れが変わります
Then we can't flow to
そうなると、そこに流れることはできません
land inside
中に着陸する
it will be blocked
それはブロックされるでしょう
Then we can see that the terrain is actually changing the state of the typhoon's movement
すると実際に地形が台風の動きの状態を変えていることが分かります。
So if we want to make more accurate typhoon predictions
より正確な台風予測をしたい場合は
It may be necessary to have a better understanding of how terrain affects typhoons
地形が台風にどのような影響を与えるかをより深く理解する必要があるかもしれない
This is also one of the reasons why it is more difficult for us to predict typhoons
これも台風の予測が難しい理由の一つです。
What about the last example?
最後の例はどうでしょうか？
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
Many people have raised their hands to affect this in an event in Shuo
周王のイベントで多くの人がこれに影響を与えるために手を挙げました
Meiji Typhoon
明治台風
You may also know when this typhoon occurs
この台風がいつ発生するかも知れるかもしれません
it's raining a lot here
ここでは雨がたくさん降っています
Especially in the Shuao area
特に朔澳地区では
But where is the typhoon?
しかし、台風はどこにあるのでしょうか？
Do you have any impression
何か感想はありますか
where was the typhoon at that time
その時台風はどこにありましたか
When Typhoon Maegi occurred
メーギ台風発生時
Typhoon Meiji is not in Taiwan at all
台風明治は台湾にまったくありません
He is over the South China Sea
彼は南シナ海の上にいる
he passed the philippines
彼はフィリピンを通過した
He is so far away
彼はとても遠くにいる
we call it a
私たちはそれを と呼んでいます
Typical effect called Qiutai
Qiutaiと呼ばれる代表的な効果
Everyone, if we see you again this fall
みなさん、この秋また会えたら
When a typhoon approaches us
台風が近づいてくると
Notice if the term is mentioned
この用語が言及されているかどうかに注意してください
in autumn
秋に
Typhoons sometimes go very low
台風は時々非常に低くなります
in the South China Sea
在南海上
You can see that they are all in this area
すべてこのエリアにあることがわかります
are near the South China Sea
南シナ海の近くにある
But Taiwan is raining
でも台湾は雨が降ってる
how so
どうして
then there is one
それなら1つあります
I'm on this topic
私はこの話題についています
There are also some research results
いくつかの研究結果もあります
Then I made a schematic diagram like this
次に、このような模式図を作成しました
typhoon though
台風だけど
In the South China Sea, but its airflow is like this
南シナ海ですが気流はこんな感じです
It just started with autumn and the low atmosphere
秋が始まったばかりで、空気が低い
The atmosphere below about 1500 meters has the northeast monsoon
標高約1500メートル以下の大気は北東モンスーンの影響を受けています
start to strengthen
強化を開始する
because we know autumn is coming
秋が来るのを知っているから
Gradually the northeast monsoon
徐々に北東モンスーンが到来
Then their two winds will meet here
そうすれば二つの風はここで出会うだろう
will be on the east side of Taiwan to the northeast corner
台湾の東側、北東の角にあります
form this conforming airflow
この適合する空気の流れを形成します
Then the corresponding airflow will rise if it is blocked by the mountain
そうすると、山に遮られると対応する気流が上昇します。
that would result in the so-called
それはいわゆる
easy to produce more rainfall
より多くの降雨量を生み出しやすい
So the rain falls on the east side of Taiwan
台湾の東側に雨が降ります
What about this effect?
この効果についてはどうでしょうか？
Some people call it the co-hosting effect
これを共同主催効果と呼ぶ人もいます
refers to the swirling airflow of a typhoon
台風の渦巻く気流のことを指します
with northeast monsoon
北東モンスーンの影響で
an effect of co-existence
共存の効果
Then this effect happens in autumn
そして、この効果は秋に起こります
So what we call the Qiutai effect
私たちが Qiutai 効果と呼ぶもの
There are often typhoons far away from us in autumn
秋は台風が遠くから来ることが多いです
caused major disasters in Taiwan
台湾で大災害を引き起こした
Just like the typhoon over there
まるで向こうの台風のように
Then I spent 30 minutes briefly introducing many basic characteristics of typhoons to everyone.
さて、30分かけて台風の多くの基本的な特徴を簡単に紹介しましたが、
Then in the last paragraph of the first stage today, I will tell you that the problem of typhoon is not just the typhoon itself.
それでは、今日の第１ステージの最後の段落で、台風の問題は台風そのものだけではないということをお伝えします。
Now a topic that many people in the scientific community are concerned about is that if our climate changes
現在、科学界の多くの人々が懸念しているテーマは、もし気候が変化したら
Will our typhoon-like storms change accordingly?
台風のような嵐もそれに応じて変化するのでしょうか？
How is typhoon related to climate?
台風と気候はどのように関係しているのでしょうか？
Then I will use a few simple slides to report some progress in this regard
次に、いくつかの簡単なスライドを使用して、この点に関する進捗状況を報告します。
Then this is a picture that you may be more familiar with.
次に、これはあなたがよく知っているかもしれない写真です。
It's too much to talk about is that this is all the temperature observations we have all over the world
世界中で観測された気温のデータがこれだけだということは、あまりにも話しすぎます。
An average of observations of the Earth's surface temperature
地球の表面温度の観測値の平均
We see that from the last century all the way to our past
前世紀から過去に至るまで、
temperature over the past few years
ここ数年の気温
Characteristics of changes in global mean surface temperature
地球の平均表面温度の変化の特徴
Then we obviously see
そうすれば明らかにわかります
It's a well-known feature
よく知られた機能です
is talking about
について話しています
The phenomenon of global warming that we have experienced in the last hundred years
過去100年間に私たちが経験した地球温暖化現象
to the past hundred years or so
過去百年くらいまで
Our global surface temperature has increased
地球の表面温度が上昇しました
about 0.74 degrees
約0.74度
that doesn't seem like much
それはあまりないようです
because we go from morning to night
朝から夜まで行くから
In winter, the weather changes by more than ten degrees.
冬には天気が10度以上変わります。
So why should we worry about this 0.74 degree?
では、なぜこの 0.74 度を心配する必要があるのでしょうか?
Because this 0.74 is a global average
この 0.74 は世界平均であるため、
You want the global average to be
世界平均を次のようにしたいと考えています。
To increase there is a systematic increase so much
増加するには計画的に増加する必要があります
Indicates that our climate is changing
気候が変化していることを示しています
Then this is not a completely negligible data
そうすると、これは完全に無視できるデータではありません
Then this obvious change
すると、この明らかな変化が
That's what everyone cares about right now
それが今みんなが気にしていることだよ
global warming issue
地球温暖化問題
So what are the reasons for this phenomenon?
では、この現象の原因は何でしょうか?
That might be another speech to talk about
それはまた話すべきスピーチかもしれません。
For example, the birth effect, the human-induced birth effect, etc.
例えば、出産効果、人為的出産効果などです。
So what we're going to talk about today is
それで、今日私たちが話そうとしているのは、
under such a condition
そのような状況下で
Scientists or scholars who we are very concerned about social economy will come out
社会経済を非常に懸念している科学者や学者が出てくるだろう
Our Future Affects Our Rainfall
私たちの将来は降雨量に影響を与える
and storm system
そしてストームシステム
Will there be systemic changes as well?
システム的な変更はありますか?
He will also be characteristically different
彼はまた特徴的に異なるでしょう
then to understand the problem
それから問題を理解するために
especially the typhoon
特に台風
We're going to start with the most basic research
最も基礎的な研究から始めます
This research is very basic
この研究は非常に基礎的なものです
show us some clues
いくつかの手がかりを見せてください
what eyebrows
何の眉毛
This is a very well-known research scholar
この人は非常に有名な研究者です
When he puts the world's typhoons at their strongest
彼が世界の台風を最強にしたとき
how strong is he
彼はどのくらい強いですか
Compared with the sea temperature conditions at that time
当時の海水温状況と比較
as a study of every point
あらゆる点の研究として
Under certain conditions, there is a typhoon whose intensity reaches 40 meters, etc.
条件によっては、強度が40メートルに達する台風などもあります。
He just clicked out every point, so many points
彼はすべてのポイントをクリックしただけです、非常に多くのポイント
There are the North Atlantic Ocean and the Northeast Pacific Ocean respectively, which are near the coast of Mexico
それぞれ北大西洋と北東太平洋があり、メキシコの海岸近くにあります。
And the Pacific Ocean in the Northwest is near us
そして北西部の太平洋は私たちの近くにあります
All points find a common feature
すべての点で共通の特徴が見つかります
This common feature is that we found that if the sea temperature is higher,
この共通点は、海水温が高いと、
The lowest distribution of typhoon is still so low, but the maximum value of the strongest and strongest part is getting bigger and bigger
台風の最低分布はまだ低いですが、最も強い部分の最大値はますます大きくなっています
In other words, roughly one of the properties of an observation that appears to be
言い換えれば、およそ次のように見える観測のプロパティの 1 つです。
As long as the sea temperature is relatively high, the range where the typhoon may reach the strongest intensity will be relatively strong
海水温が比較的高い限り、台風が最も強い勢力に達する範囲は比較的強いでしょう。
Just like the cover given by this red line
この赤い線が示す表紙のように
Vertices are getting bigger and bigger
頂点がどんどん大きくなっていく
But what about individual typhoons?
では、個々の台風についてはどうなのでしょうか？
big and small
大小
incomparably larger
無間的比較大
But its strongest is bigger
でも一番強いのはもっと大きい
so its average
だからその平均
will go up a bit
少し上がります
Average typhoon from here to here
ここからここまでの平均的な台風
about this strong
この強さについて
But the average from here to here
しかし、ここからここまでの平均
Average values ​​at this sea temperature are here
この海水温の平均値はこちら
So basically it's telling us
基本的にそれは私たちに伝えていることです
when we have global warming
地球温暖化が起こると
higher sea temperature
比較高的海溫
may offer more favorable conditions
より有利な条件を提示してくれるかもしれない
Give the typhoon a chance to be stronger
台風にさらに強くなるチャンスを与えてください
But of course there are a few typhoons
もちろん台風もいくつかありますが、
For different reasons the comparison is not very strong
さまざまな理由から、この比較はあまり強力ではありません
that's possible
それは可能です
But its statistical average properties
しかし、その統計的平均特性
will be stronger
強くなるだろう
What about this feature?
この機能についてはどうですか?
a few years ago
数年前
There is a very well-known research unit
非常に有名な研究ユニットがあります
That
それか
I just happened to serve in this research unit in the past
私はたまたま過去にこの研究ユニットに所属していました
called Princeton University
プリンストン大学と呼ばれる
geodynamics
地球力学
Fluid Power Laboratory
流体動力研究室
they use computers
彼らはコンピューターを使用します
to simulate this feature
この機能をシミュレートするには
This characteristic is to say
この特徴はつまり、
in a modern climate
現代の気候では
The distribution of typhoon intensity is roughly like this
台風の強度分布は大体こんな感じ
Then here is the central air pressure of the typhoon
では、台風の中心気圧はこんな感じです。
That is the number of typhoon occurrences
では、これが台風の発生数です。
In other words
言い換えると
If the line moves west and left,
線が西と左に移動すると、
The lower the central air pressure, the stronger the typhoon
中心気圧が低いほど台風は強くなる
So here is the frequency distribution plot of the past distribution
これが過去の分布の度数分布プロットです
So this is the later, rougher time limit?
ということは、これは後者の、より大まかな制限時間ということでしょうか？
is talking
話しています
100 years later
100年後
If our planet's carbon dioxide doubled
地球の二酸化炭素が2倍になったら
After that doubled
その後は2倍になりました
Global temperatures could increase by a few degrees C after
地球の気温はその後数℃上昇する可能性があります
new climate line
新しい気候ライン
The typhoon that their computer sees
コンピューターが見た台風
The distribution of the activities of the situation
状況のアクティビティの分布
Then the entire line moves to the left on average.
次に、ライン全体が平均して左に移動します。
That means it does change in average strength
つまり、平均強度が変化するということです
more obvious
より明らかな
So what was asked above
それで、上で尋ねられたのは
As for this question, their answer is yes, it will be stronger
この質問に関しては、彼らの答えは「はい、強くなります」です。
But I added a butt
でもお尻も追加しました
We also see that this total area represents the total number of typhoons
また、この総面積が台風の総数を表していることもわかります。
but slightly reduced
でもわずかに減った
In other words, we have more strong typhoons around the world
言い換えれば、世界中でさらに強い台風が発生しているということです。
But the total number of typhoons has decreased
しかし、台風の総数は減少しました
In other words
言い換えると
Smaller and weaker typhoons are also less and more
小型で弱い台風も少なくなってきました
That is to say, the whole world concentrates the main energy in a specific relatively strong typhoon.
つまり、世界全体が特定の比較的強い台風に主なエネルギーを集中させているのです。
Such changes can indeed have an impact on our lives and our environment
このような変化は実際に私たちの生活や環境に影響を与える可能性があります
This feature is our climate system
この機能は私たちの気候システムです
After warming, it is possible to create more strong typhoons
温暖化後はさらに強い台風が発生する可能性がある
Then this one is the result of a single study
それでは、これは単一の研究の結果です
currently published
現在出版されている
However, in recent years there have been more new results
しかし、近年さらに新たな成果も出てきています
Both reflect similar consistent features
どちらも同様の一貫した機能を反映しています
This feature refers to the
この機能は、
The future is actually not just typhoons
未来は実は台風だけじゃない
under the new climate
新しい気候の下で
warmer
暖かい
Under this global warming climate pattern
この地球温暖化の気候パターンの下では
Our storms may also be stronger
私たちの嵐もさらに強くなるかもしれない
but at the same time
しかし同時に
drought in places where water is scarce
水が不足している場所での干ばつ
That is, our climate is extreme.
つまり、私たちの気候は極端です。
Then this is the result of what we call polarization
これはいわゆる二極化の結果です
Of course it belongs to
もちろんそれはに属します
Make our climate important to our survival
気候を私たちの生存にとって重要なものにする
In fact there are larger
実際にはもっと大きなものもあります
Threats and challenges exist
脅威と課題が存在する
So far this issue
これまでのところこの問題
still under study
まだ研究中です
is what we are currently engaged in
私たちが現在取り組んでいることは
A Hot Topic in Atmospheric Research
大気研究の注目のトピック
what i just said
私が今言ったこと
slightly simpler
もう少し単純な
In fact, there are many details
実は細かい部分がたくさんあるのですが、
there are still some uncertainties
まだいくつかの不確実性があります
There are also some scientists who have many
多くの研究を行っている科学者もいます。
Different theories and different views
さまざまな理論とさまざまな見解
Then these have to be clarified with updated research.
そして、これらは最新の研究によって明らかにされる必要があります。
But I think the concept I'm talking about so far is roughly
しかし、私がこれまで話している概念は大まかに言うと、
It's acceptable, you can take him
それは受け入れられます、あなたは彼を連れて行ってもいいです
take home
家に持って帰る
what about this question
この質問はどうですか
A few years ago the World Meteorological Organization of the United Nations convened many scientists
数年前、国連世界気象機関は多くの科学者を招集しました。
meeting together
一緒に会う
Then I happened to participate in this conference, which was quite interesting at the end of 2006.
そして、2006 年末にたまたまこのカンファレンスに参加したのですが、これは非常に興味深いものでした。
Meeting in Costa Rica, singing poems and leaving home
コスタリカで出会い、詩を歌い、家を出る
That
それか
then i will go to this country for a meeting
それから私は会議のためにこの国に行きます
The happiest and most gratifying thing
一番幸せで一番嬉しいこと
The first visa-free because it is a country with diplomatic relations with us
国交があるため初のビザ不要国
The second is the holiday between us to visit his national park is the National Park of the Living Mountain
2 番目の休暇は、彼の国立公園であるリビング マウンテン国立公園を訪れるためです。
You may not believe it
信じられないかもしれない
There are only two flags in the entire national park
国立公園全体に旗は 2 つだけです
One is the national flag of Geshi Dalijia and Dalijia
一つは格氏大理家と大理家の国旗です。
The national flag of the Republic of China is all over the mountain
中華民国の国旗が山全体にあります
why
なぜ
Because that national park belongs to Renyang of the Republic of China
その国立公園は中華民国の仁陽に属しているため
But it's a very, very positive thing
でもそれはとてもとてもポジティブなことだよ
So it's also gratifying
なのでそれも嬉しいです
but
しかし
What I want to apologize to everyone is that we broke up the next year.
皆さんに謝りたいのは、翌年別れてしまったということです。
so
それで
I haven't been back yet
まだ戻っていない
but anyway
とにかく
what about this meeting
この会議はどうですか
Basically, I made a few conclusions, saying that this issue is very, very important.
基本的に、この問題は非常に非常に重要であるということで、いくつかの結論を出しました。
but there are some
でもいくつかあります
some places we're not sure yet
まだよくわかっていない場所もある
is it right
それは正しいですか
more research needed
さらなる研究が必要
what is the future
未来は何ですか
under new climate conditions
新しい気候条件下で
Those of us who create natural disasters with severe weather like typhoons
台風などの荒天で自然災害を起こす私たち
or good rain
または良い雨
How to change systematically
体系的に変えるにはどうすればよいか
more research is needed
さらなる研究が必要です
that many
それほど多くの
Scientists are still working on this
科学者たちはまだこれに取り組んでいます
Well, another interesting topic I mentioned at the beginning is typhoons.
さて、冒頭で触れたもう一つの興味深い話題は台風です。
A symbiosis with the ocean
海との共生
There is no typhoon without ocean
海がなければ台風もない
Typhoons are only produced on warm oceans
台風は暖かい海でのみ発生します
Obviously the ocean is a very important player
海が非常に重要な役割を果たしているのは明らかです
Among our many scientists
私たちの多くの科学者の中に
Some research results that have only been discovered in the past few decades
過去数十年の間に発見されたばかりの研究結果もあります
discovered that the ocean provides powerful conditions
海洋が強力な条件を提供していることを発見した
let the typhoon develop
台風が発達するように
But our typhoon is also very interesting
でも、私たちの台風もとても興味深いです
Typhoons also affect the ocean
台風は海にも影響を与えます
Because the wind of the typhoon blows on the sea
海は台風の風が吹くので
Give the ocean very strong this we say kerrik
海に非常に強い力を与えてください、これを私たちはケリックと言います
will blow the ocean
海を吹き飛ばすだろう
because the ocean moves too
海も動くから
This move will flip the ocean
この動きは海をひっくり返すだろう
makes the ocean
海を作る
We know the ocean temperature is structured like this
海の温度は次のように構成されていることがわかっています
The temperature is getting colder as we go down
気温が下がれば上がるほど寒くなってきます
there's a place on the surface of the ocean that we call the mixed layer
海の表面には混合層と呼ばれる場所があります
About tens of meters above the surface of the ocean
海面上約数十メートル
Up to a range of 100 meters at most?
最大100メートルの範囲までですか？
These places have higher temperatures
こういった場所は気温が高いです
Then there's the cold sea water
それから冷水です
cold all the way to the bottom of the sea
海の底までずっと寒い
The water on the surface of our oceans may have
私たちの海の表面の水には、
For example, the temperature of 27, 28 degrees
たとえば、気温が27度、28度の場合、
But it's only 20 degrees below 100 meters
でも、気温は100メートル下でわずか20度です
when the typhoon blows across the ocean
台風が海を越えるとき
the ocean will turn
海は変わるだろう
That's because of the wind
それは風のせいです
The sea caused by this typhoon
今回の台風でできた海
Up and down exchange of upper seawater
上層的海水的上下的交換
This process of mixing corners
この角を混ぜる工程
will bring the cold sea water up
冷たい海水を引き上げるだろう
After the typhoon cools down
台風が涼しくなったら
maybe a few degrees
おそらく数度
Then the sea temperature that was originally favorable for the development of typhoons
すると、もともと台風の発達に適していた海水温が
not enough
十分でない
after not enough
十分ではなかった後
The typhoon will weaken or even dissipate
台風は弱まるか、消滅するでしょう
Then you can see this example
次に、この例を見ることができます
This is a typhoon that happened in 2001
これは2001年に発生した台風です
That typhoon is called Typhoon Billis.
その台風は台風ビリスと呼ばれています。
Maybe you are not familiar with
たぶんあなたはよく知らないかもしれません
But this typhoon is very interesting
しかし、今回の台風は非常に興味深いです
Our first in Taiwan
初めての台湾
The second one, just mentioned the first modernized radar was on July 23, 1996
2 つ目は、最初に近代化されたレーダーが 1996 年 7 月 23 日に設置されたと先ほど述べました。
The second one was set in July 2001
2 番目の設定は 2001 年 7 月に設定されました
The one located on Green Island
緑島にあるもの
After that radar is set up,
レーダーを設置したら、
less than a month
1ヶ月未満
I have experienced it, experienced the strongest new typhoon in that era
体験しました、当時最強の新台風を体験しました
directly across from Green Island
グリーン島の真向かい
Very amazing, this is not something that can be explained by science
すごいですね、これは科学で説明できるものではありません
That
それか
After this one passed through, everyone saw that he just passed through Green Island
この人が通過した後、誰もが彼がちょうど緑島を通過したことに気づきました
The radar is back
レーダーが戻ってきた
It took a year to rebuild
再建には1年かかった
But
しかし
After reconstruction, it was rebuilt with the same standard, and no typhoon of the same intensity has passed by until now.
建て替え後は同じ基準で建て替えられ、現在まで同規模の台風は通過していません。
survived until now
今まで生き残る
It's just unfortunate that he
ただ残念なことに、彼は
He has a design limit
彼にはデザインの限界がある
Because the cost of designing a radar that can withstand stronger winds is much higher
強風に耐えられるレーダーの設計コストがはるかに高くなるため
So he designed to say this
それで彼はこう言うつもりだった
should
したほうがいい
There is a small chance that a typhoon will pass by
台風が通過する可能性は低いです
It turned out just right
それはまさにぴったりでした
They were all encountered within a month of completion.
それらはすべて完成後 1 か月以内に発生しました。
But it's been fine since then
でもそれ以来大丈夫です
This typhoon is back
この台風が帰ってきました
Before the typhoon passed by, he did not reach Taiwan
台風が通過する前に彼は台湾に着きませんでした
Please tell us about the satellite data
衛星データについて教えてください
The temperature of the water on the east side of his typhoon passing by
台風が通過する東側の水温
massive reduction
大幅な削減
What is the extent of this reduction?
この削減の範囲はどの程度ですか?
Basically can reach 4 to 5 degrees
基本的には4〜5度に達する可能性があります
So the whole sea is cold
だから海全体が冷たい
Then the typhoon will weaken slightly once he cools down
その後、台風は涼しくなったら少し弱まるでしょう
In other words
言い換えると
We the ocean are playing for us
私たち海は私たちのために遊んでいます
A machine of nature that adjusts the intensity of typhoons
台風の強さを調整する自然の機械
The ocean automatically tells the typhoon to brake
海は自動的に台風にブレーキを告げる
On the one hand, the ocean provides energy to make the typhoon grow
一方で、海は台風を成長させるエネルギーを提供します。
But when the typhoon rises to a certain level
しかし、台風がある程度の大きさになると、
The effect of this cold water of the ocean
この冷たい海の役割
I will tell the typhoon to speak slowly
台風にゆっくり話してあげるよ
don't get stronger
強くならないでください
Then this function is also a very interesting
それからこの機能も非常に興味深いです
Scientific question
科学的な質問
What if this effect is not well understood?
この効果がよく理解されていない場合はどうなるでしょうか?
It is difficult for you to predict how strong the typhoon will develop
台風がどれくらいの強さに発達するかを予測するのは難しい
That's us too, but our ocean observation data is relatively limited.
私たちもそうですが、海洋観測データは比較的限られています。
Therefore, our prediction of the intensity of the typhoon is also affected by this ocean factor.
したがって、台風の強さの予測もこの海洋要因に影響されます。
I have a colleague who has done a really good job with this research on colleagues
私には同僚に関するこの調査で非常に良い仕事をした同僚がいます
I have a joint research with him
私は彼と共同研究をしています
What about my colleague, Teacher Lin Yiyi?
私の同僚のリン・イーイー先生はどうですか？
He also noted that he used a large number of satellite observations
同氏はまた、多数の衛星観測を利用したことにも言及した。
can tell where the ocean is warmer and thicker
海がどこでより暖かくて厚いかがわかります
If the temperature of the ocean is thicker, the ocean is thicker
海の温度が高ければ、海も厚くなる
The typhoon has less disturbance to it
台風の影響が少ない
Because the cold sea water cannot come up in the deep place
深いところは冷たい海水が上がって来れないので
Under such ocean conditions, the typhoon may become very strong.
このような海洋状況では、台風が非常に強力になる可能性があります。
So this one example here is telling us that the ocean
この一例は、海が次のことを示しています。
Some places are very warm and thick, some places are colder
非常に暖かく厚い場所もあれば、より寒い場所もあります
red is warm
赤は暖かいです
since 2003
2003年以来
There is a typhoon causing serious disaster in Busan, South Korea
韓国の釜山で台風による甚大な被害が発生しています
It was developed to the strongest stage
最強のステージへ発展しました
when passing through this area
このエリアを通過するときに
in the pacific
太平洋で
Just passed a very, very warm warm water
とてもとても温かいお湯を通過したところです
the warm zone we call the ocean
私たちが海と呼ぶ暖かい地帯
Teacher Lin Yiyi noticed that
リン・イーイー先生はそれに気づきました
This typhoon called MIMI
この台風はMIMIと呼ばれています
Typhoon MIMI is passing through this area
台風MIMIがこの地域を通過中です
It's as strong as a triple jump
三段ジャンプ並みの威力です
It changed from a typhoon of the first category to a second category
第一種台風から第二種台風に変わりました
Change the third level, the fourth level, to the fifth level yellow
3番目のレベル、4番目のレベルを5番目のレベルの黄色に変更します
it just passes through this area
このエリアを通過するだけです
Because the ocean is thick enough
海は厚いから
So that natural restriction can't happen
自然な制限が起こらないように
Because the warm water is blocked very below
温水がかなり下でブロックされているため、
In the deep sea below 100 meters
水深100メートル以下の深海で
so it grows
それで成長する
This particle happens to be a few years later
この粒子はたまたま数年後です
There is a very good proof
非常に良い証拠があります
This proof happened in 2005
この証拠は 2005 年に起こりました
very different
とても違う
one in the south of america
一つはアメリカ南部にある
everyone is familiar with
誰もがよく知っています
This is the giant peak called Catalina
これがカタリナと呼ばれる巨大な峰です
This giant peak first landed
この巨大な峰が初めて上陸した
This New Europe-faced area
新しいヨーロッパに面したこの地域
caused thousands of casualties
数千人の死傷者を出した
This giant peak is also God's will
この巨峰も神の意志
really unfortunate
本当に残念な
When this giant peak just passed by here
この巨大な峰がちょうどここを通り過ぎたとき
It was originally just a second-level giant peak.
元々は単なる第二級の巨峰だった。
But just in this season
ただ、この季節だけは
America has an ocean current
アメリカには海流がある
This ocean current we call lasing current
この海流をレーザー海流と呼びます
The larger scope of this set of flow is from this side
この一連の流れのより大きな範囲はこちら側からのものです
Then on the Cuban side will pass here
その後、キューバ側がここを通過します
up through the east side of florida
フロリダの東側を通って
This current is called the Mexican Pill Current
この海流はメキシコピル海流と呼ばれています
that is a warm current
それは暖流です
warm current from the south
南からの暖流
This warm current in this Atlantic Ocean
この大西洋の暖流
usually flow like this
通常はこのように流れます
But this warm current has an instability
しかし、この暖流には不安定性があります。
occasionally twists out
時々ねじれてしまう
and will come out
そして出てくるでしょう
Sleeve flow
スリーブの流れ
it becomes a loop
それはループになる
Our Chinese translation complete flow
弊社の中国語翻訳完了の流れ
just at that time it came out
ちょうどその時に出てきた
It's like Mazu went around
媽祖が回ったみたいだ
around the gulf of mexico
メキシコ湾のあたり
would have been gulf of mexico
メキシコ湾だったでしょう
The sea water of this bay
この湾の海水は
is very very shallow mixed layer
非常に浅い混合層です
That is to say
つまり
the water is cold under it
その下の水は冷たいです
easy to run up to
簡単に駆け上がることができる
So most typhoons pass through the Gulf of Mexico
そのため、ほとんどの台風はメキシコ湾を通過します。
weakens soon
すぐに弱くなる
But that time I just met this warm cow passing by
でもその時ちょうど通りかかった温かい牛に出会ったんです
So this typhoon is blessed here
だから、この台風はここで祝福されています
The result of this blessing
この祝福の結果は
it goes from level two to level five
レベル2からレベル5になります
Just leave this warm cow when you are at your strongest
あなたが一番強いときは、この暖かい牛を放っておいてください
then slowly fades away
その後ゆっくりと消えていきます
But it landed at level 4
しかし、レベル4に到達しました
Originally the United States designed this one
もともとこれはアメリカが設計したものです
Time to watch out for this one in New Orleans Beachview
ニューオーリンズ・ビーチビューでこれに注目する時が来ました
It is designed to resist...
抵抗するように設計されています...
Category 3 hurricane
カテゴリー3のハリケーン
Mainly because the hurricane in this place can't be that strong
この場所のハリケーンはそれほど強いはずがないからです
will weaken
弱くなるだろう
But that year happened to encounter this warm current
しかしその年はたまたまこの暖流に遭遇した
So the ocean is so important
だから海はとても大切なんです
Of course this unfortunate
もちろん、これは不幸です
This accident is the match of fate
この事故は運命の出会いだ
In addition to the excavation in the New European Union area
新欧州連合地域の発掘に加えて
Then we must rely on this precaution to protect
その場合、私たちはこの予防策に頼って身を守る必要があります。
But watch out for the last three places where the embankment breaks
ただし、最後の 3 か所は堤防が決壊しているので注意してください。
So the whole city is buried under the flood
それで街全体が洪水に埋もれてしまう
on our east coast
私たちの東海岸で
In fact there is a similar one
実は似たようなのがあるんです
characteristic ocean currents
特徴的な海流
This ocean current we all know is
私たちが知っているこの海流は、
our black grass
私たちの黒い草
This black grass is passing through the east side of Taiwan to the north
この黒い草は台湾の東側を北へ通過しています
but
しかし
What about his organization?
彼の組織はどうなっているのでしょうか？
main
主要
It is obvious here that in this area
ここで明らかなのは、この領域では
What about the black grass?
黒い草はどうですか？
right now we
今、私たちは
It is suspected that Typhoon Nali was around here in the first place.
そもそも台風ナリがこのあたりにあったのではないかと思われます。
This one Nali can be here in September
このナリは9月にここに来ることができます
Survival last affects Taiwan
サバイバル最後の影響が台湾に及ぶ
It may be closely related to passing through the black grass
黒い草を通過することと密接に関連している可能性があります
So if we want to understand typhoons
台風を理解したいなら
Not only the atmosphere but also the ocean
大気だけでなく海も
Both must pass
どちらも合格しなければならない
may be more precise
より正確かもしれない
Can judge how it will develop in the future
将来どのように発展するかを判断できる
even predict it
それを予測することさえ
those are some examples
これらはいくつかの例です
Then at the end of today, I will introduce to you
それでは今日の最後にご紹介します
How can we use the modern scientific method
現代の科学的手法をどのように活用するか
to enhance our understanding of the issue
問題についての理解を深めるために
Ok, the last question for today's first period
さて、今日の1時間目の最後の質問です
Many people must want to ask
聞きたい人も多いはず
Can a typhoon be reformed?
台風は修復できるのか？
how
どうやって
You may have heard many such sayings.
あなたもそのような言葉をたくさん聞いたことがあるかもしれません。
that in fact we are in
実際に私たちがいるのは
National Geographic Discovery
ナショナル ジオグラフィックの発見
There are topics discussing whether the typhoon can be transformed
台風が変身できるかどうかが話題になっている
Is the answer Yes or No?
答えはイエスかノーか?
I wrote an article for Scientist magazine in 2006
2006 年にサイエンティスト誌に記事を書きました
talk about this
このことについて話してください
In simple terms
簡単な言葉で
yes there are many different ideas
はい、さまざまなアイデアがあります
Some of these ideas
これらのアイデアの一部
scientifically based
科学に基づいた
Most of them have scientific basis
それらのほとんどには科学的根拠があります
But in essence
しかし本質的には
It's something that our human technology can't do at present.
それは、現時点では私たちの人間のテクノロジーでは不可能なことです。
So I listed him as a little bit
それで私は彼を少しリストしました
close to sci-fi
SFに近い
But it's a good idea
しかし、それは良い考えです
let me talk to you
話させてください
You can go back and think about it
戻って考えてもいいよ
do you have any ideas
あなたはなにか考えはありますか
what to do
何をすべきか
change typhoon
台風を変える
In America since the 1960s
アメリカでは1960年代から
From 1980 to 20 years
1980年から20年間
proposed an idea
アイデアを提案した
A large research project called
と呼ばれる大規模な研究プロジェクト
Broken plan
破綻した計画
Broken Wind Project
ブロークン・ウィンド・プロジェクト
What about this shattering plan?
この衝撃的な計画はどうでしょうか？
It was proposed by a group of excellent scientists
優秀な科学者のグループによって提案されました
their idea is to say
彼らの考えはこう言うことだ
What if we can be around the typhoon?
台風の周りにいることができたらどうしますか？
to do artificial rainfall
人工降雨をする
artificial rain
人工雨
Just sprinkle some chemical camp and so on
ケミカルキャンプなどを振りかけるだけ
Let the typhoon around
台風を一周させてください
The atmosphere condenses and rains at the periphery of the typhoon in advance
台風の周囲では大気が凝結して事前に雨が降る
After the typhoon came in, the water vapor condensed outside ahead of time
台風が来て、外では水蒸気が先に結露した
The eyewall inside the typhoon was wiped out.
台風の内側の目壁は全滅した。
Or we say being chocked
あるいは、窒息しているとも言います
suffocated
窒息した
it has no water vapor
水蒸気が無い
it will dissipate
それは消えてしまうだろう
If the main winds of the typhoon are all turning outside
台風の本風が全部外に向いたら
like an ice skater he was spinning really fast
アイススケーターのように彼はとても速く回転していました
when he opened his hand
彼が手を開いたとき
Because of the conservation of absolute foot momentum
絶対的な足の運動量が保存されるため
The speed of his entire rotation slows down.
全体の回転速度が遅くなります。
The idea is entirely based on physics
このアイデアは完全に物理学に基づいています
But they have been flying planes for more than ten years
しかし彼らは10年以上飛行機を操縦している
I went into the typhoon and sprinkled a lot of these phones
台風の中に行って、たくさんの電話を撒き散らした
This so-called agglomeration
このいわゆる凝集
to help the typhoon rain on the periphery
台風周辺での雨を助けるために
Finally, analyze the result
最後に結果を分析します
to the early 1980s
1980年代初頭まで
The United States finally invited a very famous scientist
米国はついに非常に有名な科学者を招待した
Zhu Zhiying
朱志英
Made a committee to see if it worked after all
結局それがうまくいくかどうかを確認するために委員会を作りました
As a result, the research report showed that
その結果、調査報告書は次のことを示しました。
they can't prove
彼らは証明できない
with or without home
家があってもなくても
Does the strength of the typhoon affect
台風の強さが影響するのか
So that project ended up being discontinued.
それでそのプロジェクトは結局中止になりました。
Then this idea will stay in this city forever
そうすればこの想いは永遠にこの街に残るだろう
because we want to be efficient
効率的でありたいから
with limited aircraft resources
限られた航空機リソースの中で
To transform the entire radius of hundreds of kilometers
半径数百キロメートル全体を変えるには
Typhoon rainfall in a large environment
広い環境での台風降雨
Actually that cost a lot
実はそれにはかなりの費用がかかりました
and existing tools are not capable of implementing at scale
既存のツールでは大規模な実装ができない
so can't do it
だからそれはできない
Unless of course the only way to do it is to do it in the computer
もちろん、それを行う唯一の方法がコンピュータで行うことである場合を除きます。
That might be possible, but it's practically impossible at the moment.
それは可能かもしれませんが、現時点では事実上不可能です。
Another very interesting idea
もう一つの非常に興味深いアイデア
The idea is this
アイデアはこれです
We also have some very interesting active surfactants
非常に興味深い活性界面活性剤もいくつかあります
These interface agents are called Sephechon in English
これらのインターフェースエージェントは英語ではセフェションと呼ばれます。
And these interface agents
そしてこれらのインターフェースエージェントは
It's just a thin layer of ink on the sea
それは海の上の薄いインクの層に過ぎない
These inks if you can spread it out to sea
このインクを海に広げられたら
Our water will be separated from the air
私たちの水は空気から分離されるでしょう
it can't evaporate anymore
もう蒸発することはできません
Then the atmosphere will not get a source of water vapor
そうすれば、大気中に水蒸気の発生源が存在しなくなります
That typhoon might not last
あの台風は続かないかもしれない
In the computer, you can experiment and say
コンピューターでテストできます
If you block the whole ocean
海全体を塞いでしまったら
The typhoon will never come out
台風は絶対出ないよ
So scientists do experiments
そこで科学者たちは実験をします
throw these on the ocean
これを海に投げてください
And it's eco-friendly, bio-soluble, these
そしてそれは環境に優しく、生体溶解性です。
Surfection's active surfactants
Surfection の活性界面活性剤
But they were stupid and found that they couldn't stop
でも彼らは愚かで、止められないことに気づいた
Because the range of the typhoon is too large
台風の範囲が広すぎるので
If you don't give me water here
ここで水を与えてくれないと
I come from another side
私は別の側から来ました
so never stop
だから決して止まらないでください
Unless you completely block the entire sea
海全体を完全に遮断しない限り
Then this is definitely except in the virtual world of the computer
そうすると、これは間違いなくコンピューターの仮想世界以外のことです。
None other than Avatar
他ならぬアバター
have a chance to do it
それをするチャンスがある
it's an interesting topic
興味深い話題です
i have a scientist
私には科学者がいます
keep exploring
探索を続ける
Of course this is the domain of the most avant-garde research
もちろん、これは最も前衛的な研究の領域です
To really transform the typhoon
台風を本当に変えるには
Maybe even more future technologies
おそらく未来のテクノロジーはますます増えていくでしょう
Another thought is
もう一つの考えは、
satellite in the sky
空の衛星
to collect sunlight
太陽光を集めるために
concentrate sunlight on
太陽光を集中させる
Some specific areas of typhoons
台風の特定地域
heat up that area
そのエリアを温める
then look forward to say
それなら言うのを楽しみにしています
The typhoon will go in a certain direction
台風はある方向に進むでしょう
Do not come to Taiwan but go to the Philippines
台湾に来ないでフィリピンに行きなさい
right
右
this
これ
This is of course very very
これはもちろんとてもとても
unethical and immoral behavior
非倫理的かつ不道徳な行為
so
それで
Of course I was just joking
もちろん冗談だったんだけど
So that's a whole other topic
それはまったく別の話題です
Someone brought this up
誰かがこれを持ち出した
Some people have thought about it
考えたことのある人もいる
That's not possible with current technology
それは現在の技術では不可能です
but for us humans
しかし私たち人間にとっては
From a scientist's point of view
科学者の観点から
from a scientific point of view
科学的な観点から
attract us
私たちを惹きつける
Some ways to fundamentally remove the typhoon problem
台風問題を根本的に解決するいくつかの方法
However, in fact, these methods are not currently available.
しかし、実際には、これらの方法は現在利用できません。
just some ideas
ほんのいくつかのアイデア
This is my first stage today
今日が私の最初のステージです
I want to hear everyone's feedback
みんなの意見が聞きたいです
we go to the second stage
私たちは第二段階に進みます
let's have a beer
ビールを飲みましょう
Sorry, Zhongyuan Institute did not provide
申し訳ありませんが、中原研究所は提供していません
Okay, let's just imagine drinking a beer
さて、ビールを飲むところを想像してみましょう
spirit again
再び精神
I just talked to you about the disaster caused by the typhoon
先ほど台風による災害についてお話しました。
I also know the typhoon
台風もわかる
if that's not enough
それで十分でない場合
There is a book you can read
読める本があります
Then I introduced the typhoon may be related to the concept of climate
次に、台風は気候の概念に関係している可能性があることを紹介しました。
Talk to the ocean at last about the makeover
ついに変身について海と話す
Are there any current Phase 1 questions?
現在フェーズ 1 に関する質問はありますか?
Not bad, obviously everyone absorbed
悪くない、明らかにみんな夢中になっている
that's good yes
それはいいです、はい
min GPA o Canada min GPA o Toronto
カナダの最小 GPA トロントの最小 GPA
right
右
Um
えーっと
That's a broader issue than a typhoon.
それは台風よりも広い問題だ。
That
それか
that basically
それは基本的に
Thanks for reminding me
思い出させてくれてありがとう
What about the whole concept of a slideshow?
スライドショーの全体的なコンセプトについてはどうですか?
It is part of the entire disaster prevention system of the entire government
政府全体の防災体制の一環です
A more comprehensive part of thinking
思考のより包括的な部分
that other
そのほかの
They are directly related to typhoons
台風と直接比較することができます。
That
それか
The whole of our environment mentioned in it
そこに記載されている私たちの環境全体
The changes in society itself include us in Taiwan, which is an obvious feature that includes
社会そのものの変化には台湾にいる私たちも含まれており、それは明らかな特徴です。
Aging and declining birthrate
少子高齢化
Maybe he is emphasizing the concept of economic activities
経済活動という概念を強調しているのかもしれない。
and society as a whole
そして社会全体
For example, I think it should be, he may be emphasizing that
たとえば、私はそうあるべきだと思いますが、彼は次のように強調しているのかもしれません。
society has one
社会にはそれが一つある
a characteristic of aging
老化の特徴
So society is changing during this process
この過程で社会は変化する
The residents of these different age groups
こういったさまざまな年齢層の住民が
He's adapting to various disasters, maybe his conditions, etc.
彼はさまざまな災害、おそらく彼の状態などに適応しています。
different must be considered
異なることを考慮する必要がある
Yes, of course the comparison I just mentioned
はい、もちろん、先ほど述べた比較です
a bit more general
もう少し一般的な
But he is the whole big country
しかし彼は大きな国全体です
One related to security and disaster issues
安全保障や災害に関するもの
part of
的一環
So to think more broadly
そこで、もっと広く考えると、
good
良い
Yes one more question
はい、もう一つ質問です
good yes
いいですね、はい
then ask first
それなら最初に聞いてください
Typhoon actually my feeling
台風、実は私の気持ち
He should have the function of energy balance
彼はエネルギーバランスの機能を持っているはずです
He takes the heat from a place closer to where he eats it
食べる場所に近い場所から熱を奪う
north half
北半分
Then if we block the typhoon
じゃあ台風を阻止したら
Will it force our atmosphere
それは私たちの雰囲気を強制するのでしょうか
The energy gap between the two sides is getting bigger and bigger
両国間のエネルギー格差はますます大きくなっている
In the end, a more terrible storm came out
ついにはさらにひどい嵐が出てきました
that's a very good question
それはとても良い質問です
I will add to you
追加させていただきます
Just now this is an expert's question
ただいま専門家の質問です
our whole
私たちの全体
On Earth we know that the sun heats up more unevenly
地球上では、太陽の温度がより不均一であることがわかっています。
So it's warmer on average in the tropics.
つまり、熱帯地方の方が平均的に暖かいのです。
Heating by more radiation from the sun
太陽からのより多くの放射による暖房
The higher the tail, the less
尾部が高いほど、小さくなります
In fact, scientists have analyzed
実際、科学者たちは分析しました
That is, if our climate is to stabilize
つまり、気候が安定するとしたら
This energy must be redistributed
このエネルギーは再分配されなければなりません
reach an equilibrium
平衡に達する
Although the south is still
南はまだですが、
The equator is still warm
赤道はまだ暖かい
But at least it's not getting warmer
でも少なくとも暖かくはなってない
or the base is getting warmer
あるいは基地が暖かくなってきている
Then this effect depends on the delivery of a lot of air flow
この効果は、大量の空気流の供給に依存します。
including ocean transport
海上輸送も含めて
to adjust for temperature differences
温度差を調整するために
It is unstable when the difference is too large.
差が大きすぎると不安定になります。
its atmosphere is unstable or the ocean
大気が不安定か海洋
that if
もし
The presence of that typhoon did play an important role.
あの台風の存在は確かに重要な役割を果たしました。
It happened to be mentioned in that book
たまたまその本の中で言及されていた
Can help with this energy delivery
このエネルギー供給に役立ちます
So if this is more artificially changed
これがさらに人為的に変更された場合
is capable of disrupting the existing equilibrium of our climate
私たちの気候の既存の均衡を破壊する可能性があります
then you must
それならあなたはしなければなりません
It's going to find a new balance point
新しいバランスポイントを見つけることになるだろう
Well, that does make a difference
まあ、それは違います
to what extent
どの程度まで
Will there be other different changes?
他にも異なる変更はありますか?
What about the weather for these so-called special freaks?
いわゆる特殊な変人たちの天気はどうでしょうか？
In fact, there is research
実は研究もある
good question thanks
良い質問です、ありがとう
ok my last question for phase one
はい、フェーズ 1 に関する最後の質問です
Please tell me, if you say
と言ったら教えてください
Someday science has its way in science
いつか科学が科学の道を歩むようになる
That is to block the typhoon
それは台風を防ぐためです
Will this cause sweating?
これにより発汗の原因になるのでしょうか？
Thanks
ありがとう
Because the typhoon will bring abundant quantity
台風がたくさん持ってくるから
If there is a scientific way to stop the typhoon
科学的に台風を止める方法があるなら
no typhoon
台風はありません
Will the whole earth be a disaster of sweat?
地球全体が汗の災難となるでしょうか？
good question
良い質問
let me in fact we earth have very, very many
実際のところ、私たち地球には非常に多くのものが存在します
not a typhoon
台風ではない
But it's also a convective system that produces a lot of rainfall.
しかし、それは大量の降雨を生み出す対流システムでもあります。
The convective is the convective rain that rises from the air
対流とは空気から上昇する対流雨のことです
These systems may have a smaller range
これらのシステムの範囲は狭い場合があります
only tens of kilometers
たった数十キロ
range of several kilometers
数キロメートルの範囲
they don't really rain
彼らは本当に雨が降らない
The typhoon is one of the few cases
台風は数少ないケースの一つです
but it's very organized
しかし、それは非常に組織的です
tens to hundreds of kilometers
数十キロから数百キロ
This is a monster that combines airflow and rainfall
これは気流と雨量を組み合わせたモンスターです
is really a monster
本当にモンスターです
If this thing does not exist when
もしこれが存在しないとき
Maybe nature has other ways of adjusting
もしかしたら自然には他の調整方法があるかもしれない
how to deal with it
それにどう対処するか
I'll get to that shortly
すぐにそれについて行きます
So after we drink these four or five glasses
それで、この4、5杯を飲んだ後、
let's continue
続けましょう
Then I'll just get to your point from here
それではここから本題に入ります
In fact, we all know the typhoon forecast
実は台風の予報は皆さんご存知ですよね
actually not that good
実際にはそれほど良くありません
You can also hear that you are sometimes very demanding
時には非常に要求が厳しいことも聞くことができます
would think why can't we do better
なぜもっとうまくやれないのかと思うだろう
Why can't weather forecasts be more accurate?
なぜ天気予報はもっと正確にできないのでしょうか?
You clearly said you would log in, why didn't you come?
ログインするとはっきり言ったのに、なぜ来なかったのですか？
Then put a day off and said afterwards
それから一日休んで、その後こう言いました
Ask us to make up driving, make up passengers and make up shifts
運転の補填、乗客の補填、シフトの補填を依頼してください。
Of course that's a very crazy idea
もちろん、それは非常にクレイジーなアイデアです
But basically, you can see this example
しかし、基本的には、この例を見ることができます
Typhoon Maeji 2010
台風2010年前地
This one caused heavy rain in Suao. Do you remember this typhoon?
この台風により蘇澳に大雨が発生しましたが、この台風を覚えていますか?
it goes through the philippines
フィリピンを経由します
At that time, predictions around the world were very different.
当時、世界中の予測は大きく異なりました。
The north side of the South Park is very inconsistent
サウスパークの北側は非常に矛盾しています
wait until after it passes the philippines
フィリピンを通過するまで待ってください
Worldwide forecasts are also completely different
世界の予測も全く違う
No one knows Mo Zhong I
誰も莫忠を知らない
This is the computer's prediction
これはコンピューターの予測です
don't know where he's going
彼がどこへ行くのか分からない
Then this highlights the typhoon forecast
そして、これは台風の予報を強調します
there are many difficulties
多くの困難があります
who do you trust
あなたは誰を信頼しますか
In this example, if you choose the middle, you are right.
この例では、中央を選択すると正解です。
he ended up like this
彼は結局こうなった
Basically, when he was in the process
基本的に、彼がその過程にいたとき、
While here, the typhoon is raining heavily
ここにいる間、台風で大雨が降っています
also very strange
とても奇妙でもあります
But if you understand that this is the role of Qiutai
でも、これが秋台の役割だと理解すれば
you can understand
あなたは理解できます
Why is there rainfall caused by this co-organization?
この共同組織によって雨が降るのはなぜですか?
But if this path is different, then the shape of the rainfall
でもこの道が違うなら 雨の形も
must change completely
完全に変わらなければならない
Therefore, the entry forecast of typhoon
そのため、台風の侵入予想は
I have always wanted to understand how typhoons change
台風がどのように変化するのかを知りたいとずっと思っていました
the most basic question
最も基本的な質問
Speaking of which, we will involve
そういえば、
I'm sorry this one hasn't turned it into Chinese yet
申し訳ありませんが、これはまだ中国語に変換されていません
The progress of our entire science now
現在の私たちの科学全体の進歩
is to digitize the problem
問題をデジタル化することです
We use computers to predict typhoons
私たちはコンピューターを使って台風を予測します
But this is definitely far beyond
しかし、これは間違いなくはるかに超えています
What we now call the Dimension Doushu
今で言う次元動態
You will know when you enter the generated horoscope
生成されたホロスコープに入るとわかります
possible future
可能性のある未来
or short-term or long-term development of fate
または短期的または長期的な運命の発展
This is indeed based on our understanding of the entire
これはまさに、全体に対する私たちの理解に基づいています。
The basic operation of nature, physics, chemistry and mathematics
自然、物理、化学、数学の基本的な操作
some fundamental principles
いくつかの基本原則
Including simply speaking Newton's laws of motion
単純にニュートンの運動法則を言うことも含む
laws of thermodynamics etc.
熱力学の法則など。
to understand the fluids in our atmosphere
大気中の流体を理解する
how to change
変更する方法
take all these processes
これらすべてのプロセスを経て
with we can
私たちにはできる
Mathematical way to do it
数学的な方法
Solutions of Differential Equations
微分方程式の解法
then go find out its answer
それなら答えを探しに行ってください
Then we construct this thing called numerical mode
次に、数値モードと呼ばれるものを構築します。
if you can tell me this fluid
この液体を教えていただければ
Current state
現在の状態
I may be able to predict the future state
未来の状態を予測できるかもしれない
What about the entire computer in the world?
世界中のコンピューター全体はどうでしょうか?
progress
進捗
has a large level
大きなレベルがある
are working together to solve this problem
この問題を解決するために協力しています
as long as the computer every other year
コンピュータが隔年である限り
We all know that there is an electricity
私たちは電気があることを知っています
it will increase the speed of its operation
動作速度が向上します
degree of change
変化の程度
that's almost working with us
それは私たちとほぼ協力しています
Development of Atmospheric Computing
大気コンピューティングの開発
five years ago
5年前
In Japan there is a thing called Earth Simulator
日本には地球シミュレータというものがある
It's as big as a rain bomb
雨爆弾みたいに大きいよ
that's all in operation
それはすべて動作中です
It was the fastest computer in the world at the time
当時世界最速のコンピューターでした
Its floating point operation speed per second
1秒あたりの浮動小数点演算速度
is 40 multiplied to the power of 12
40の12乗です
so very very fast
とてもとても速い
terabytes the flux every second
テラバイト毎秒のフラックス
The updated computer is now in the United States
更新されたコンピューターは現在米国にあります
Then the US won him back
その後、米国が彼を取り戻した
back face
反回面子
in Tennessee
テネシー州で
What about the new system in the United States?
アメリカの新しい制度はどうですか？
about fifty times that
その約50倍
Now it is the Flux of two times ten to the fifteenth power
これで、2 の 10 の 15 乗のフラックスになります。
then it is faster
それなら早いです
But most of them are doing this calculation
しかし、ほとんどの人はこの計算を行っています
Understanding Changes in Our Earth's Climate
地球の気候の変化を理解する
But there is a fundamental problem with this calculation
しかし、この計算には根本的な問題があります
You may have heard
聞いたことがあるかもしれません
called this effect
これを効果と呼びます
effect called chaos
カオスと呼ばれる効果
Then if we have any uncertainty about the initial state
初期状態に不確実性がある場合は、
Future predictions are likely to get worse and worse
今後の予測はますます悪くなる可能性が高い
just a little bit
少しだけ
Ten millimeters are a thousand miles away
10ミリメートルは1000マイル離れています
It can be completely different in the end
最終的には全く違うものになる可能性がある
Then this feature was discovered by a famous scholar
その後、この特徴は有名な学者によって発見されました
That's Edward Lorenz
それはエドワード・ローレンツです
What about this teacher I studied in my school days?
私が学生時代に習ったこの先生はどうですか？
He actually has been in the past few years ago
実は彼は数年前にも来ていたんです
in his world
彼の世界では
In fact, in the past few years, it is said that they were still in the final list of the Nobel Prize in Physics.
実際、ここ数年はノーベル物理学賞の最終候補に残っていたとも言われている。
It's a pity, of course, that he died before he won the award.
もちろん、彼が受賞を待たずに亡くなったのは残念だ。
But this is a very large research contribution
しかし、これは非常に大きな研究貢献です
That effect is also called the butterfly effect.
その効果はバタフライ効果とも呼ばれます。
It makes it very difficult for us to forecast the weather or typhoon
天気や台風を予測するのは非常に困難です
Because we have no idea what a typhoon looks like in the first place
そもそも台風がどんなものか分からないから
That
それか
because of this problem
この問題のせいで
I've just been working on a research project for the past few years and I'm going to wrap up with you today with this project
私はここ数年研究プロジェクトに取り組んできましたが、今日はこのプロジェクトで締めくくりたいと思います。
The key to this is that we need better data to improve our typhoon predictions
その鍵となるのは、台風の予測を改善するにはより良いデータが必要であるということです
However, the data around the typhoon are very limited.
しかし、台風周辺のデータは非常に限られています。
Then I just mentioned that we have
それから、先ほど言いましたが、
radar
レーダー
There are satellites in the sky to assist us
空には私たちを助けてくれる衛星があります
The radar has its limit because the radar may be able to do what he does
レーダーには限界がある、なぜならレーダーは彼のやることをできるかもしれないからだ
Electromagnetic waves
電磁波
in the atmosphere
大気中で
It may be able to detect atmospheric features within two to three hundred kilometers
200～300キロメートル以内の大気の特徴を検出できる可能性がある
So when the typhoon approaches
なので、台風が近づくと、
You can tell where it's raining by looking at the radar
レーダーを見ればどこに雨が降っているかがわかります
very useful
非常有用
But if the typhoon is farther away
でも台風がもっと遠ければ
you can't even see
あなたには見えません
Satellites are hundreds of kilometers from us to 7800 kilometers
衛星は私たちから7800キロメートルまで数百キロメートル離れています
This orbiting satellite reaches the so-called 36,000 kilometers
この周回衛星はいわゆる高度 36,000 キロメートルに達します
This geostationary satellite is also monitoring the characteristics of our atmosphere
この静止衛星は大気の特性も監視しています
Then these waves through different batteries
次に、これらの波がさまざまなバッテリーを通過します
microwave, etc.
電子レンジなど
visible light infrared
可視光線赤外線
The atmospheric temperature and other information generated by various signals
気温などの各種信号による情報
It also tells us the location of typhoons, etc.
台風の位置なども教えてくれます。
But the key to a typhoon is how the wind blows
しかし、台風の鍵は風の吹き方だ
These ways we call panning
私たちがパンニングと呼ぶこれらの方法
There is no way to measure it very accurately.
非常に正確に測定する方法はありません。
That makes our initial judgment on the typhoon
それが台風に対する最初の判断となる
there are some errors
いくつかの間違いがあります
All make this chaotic effect continue to amplify
すべてがこの混沌とし​​た影響を増幅させ続けます
Then in order to solve this problem
それでは、この問題を解決するために
scientists will know
科学者なら分かるだろう
Use an airplane to detect typhoons
飛行機を使って台風を探知する
Because this is the only instrument that can put the observation
観察できるのはこれだけだから
directly to the vicinity of the typhoon
台風のすぐ近くに
direct way to measure
直接測定する方法
However, this method does have a relatively large risk
ただし、この方法には比較的大きなリスクがあります
let me speed up
スピードを上げさせてください
That
それか
in America
アメリカでは
has matured
成熟しました
They have been since 1970
彼らは1970年から続いています
It has very mature technology
非常に成熟した技術を持っています
He uses this C-130 transport plane
彼はこの C-130 輸送機を使用しました
Or this anti-submarine aircraft called P3
あるいはこのP3と呼ばれる対潜航空機
or this jet
あるいはこのジェット機
Fly around the typhoon to detect the typhoon
台風の周りを飛んで台風を探知
He throws this from the air
彼はこれを空中から投げます
The instrument used in the cold test is called Touluosong
コールドテストで使用される装置はTouluosongと呼ばれます
he is in the process of landing
彼は着陸途中だ
The process of transferring from the air to the sea
空から海へ移る過程
atmospheric information
大気情報
temperature, humidity, air pressure
温度、湿度、気圧
measure out
測る
How about measuring wind speed?
風速を測ってみたらどうでしょうか？
Because he will swing with the wind in the air
風に乗って揺れるから
shift
シフト
he can talk to
彼は話すことができます
That's the effect of the wind
それは風の影響を受けます
he can
彼はできる
He knows how much the wind will move
彼は風がどれだけ動くかを知っている
he has precise
彼は正確さを持っている
GPS location so it can make an indirect calculation of how the wind is blowing
GPS 位置情報により、風の吹き方を間接的に計算できます。
So it also measures the magnitude and direction of the wind
したがって、風の大きさと方向も測定します
then we can reconstruct the structure of the typhoon
そうすれば台風の構造を再構築できる
Especially these two C-130 and P-3 aircraft
特にこの 2 機の C-130 と P-3 航空機
It is usually crossed to the center of the typhoon
通常は台風の中心を通過します
What about after this way of flying?
この飛び方の後はどうなるでしょうか？
We can create typhoon structures in different four directions
4方向の異なる台風構造を作成可能
This is the only effective method that can fully resolve the typhoon's characteristics at present
現時点で台風の特性を完全に解決できる唯一の有効な方法です
The whole world is now only in the Atlantic Ocean that has done such work for a long time
全世界は現在、そのような仕事を長い間行ってきた大西洋だけです
Other sunny typhoons can't help
他の晴れた台風は役に立たない
Then I will be close to this job
そうすれば私はこの仕事に近づくことになります
It happened to be in 1991 when I was in graduate school
1991年、私が大学院に通っていた頃のことです。
At that time, my advisor was the author of the book I just talked about.
その時のアドバイザーが、先ほど話した本の著者でした。
he happened to have he had he was a theorist
彼はたまたま持っていた 彼は理論家だった
He would love to do a big time enlisting his theory
彼は自分の理論を取り入れて大いにやりたいと思っています
what theory
どういう理論
How do typhoons form
台風はどのようにして発生するのか
Worldwide in tropical ocean
世界中の熱帯の海で
three steps five o'clock
三歩五時
Just to answer the lady's question
女性の質問に答えるだけです
There's a lot of convection going on
対流がかなり起こっている
But most of the convection
しかし、対流のほとんどは
Clouds grow and it rains
雲が増えて雨が降る
It usually only has a lifespan of a few hours
通常、寿命は数時間しかありません
Dissipate after downloading
ダウンロード後に消える
Wait for the next cloud to grow
次の雲が成長するのを待ちます
They can't organize into a typhoon
彼らは台風を組織することができない
only very very few
ごくごく少数だけ
These convective clouds can become typhoons
この対流雲は台風になる可能性があります
our world year
私たちの世界年
Only 80 to 90 typhoons can grow
台風は80～90個しか成長しない
Here's another interesting scientific question
もう一つの興味深い科学的疑問があります
what climate is controlling this one 90
どのような気候がこれを制御しているのか 90
the magic number
魔法の数字
roughly this is a long number
おおよそこれは長い数字です
80 to 90
80～90
The total number of typhoons in the world in a year
1年間に世界中で発生した台風の総数
that's all
それで全部です
Our rations are at Northwest Sun's
私たちの食糧はノースウェストサンズにあります
The quota is about 30 or so
定員は30名程度です
That's the most in the world right here
それはここで世界で最も多いです
As for the less important places, there are about a dozen of them here.
それほど重要ではない場所については、ここに約 12 か所あります。
here are ten more
あと10個あります
just answered there
そこに答えただけです
Someone asked me why there is no typhoon in Europe when I was eating just now
さっきご飯を食べていたら、なぜヨーロッパには台風が来ないのかと聞かれました。
One is the high tail and the other is the typhoon, both headed westward.
1 つは高尾尾、もう 1 つは台風で、どちらも西に向かっています。
Then the high-tail typhoon was too cold and dissipated.
その後、ハイテール台風は寒すぎて消滅してしまいました。
In addition, it is interesting for you to ask
さらに、あなたが尋ねるのは興味深いことです
If you don't have it, it's because you don't have enough
持っていないのは、物が足りないからです
The rotation provided by the rotation of our earth is called the Coschel force
地球の自転によってもたらされる回転はコシェル力と呼ばれます
Then this interested friend can go to find the root of this problem
そうすれば、この興味のある友人はこの問題の根本を見つけに行くことができます。
But there is no here, so why?
でもここには無いのに、なぜ？
The sea temperature here is relatively cold, so there are no typhoons
ここは海水温が比較的低いので台風がありません。
Then why is the sea temperature colder here?
では、なぜここの海水温は低いのでしょうか？
It just so happens that the ocean current over there has the eternal current over there
たまたま、向こうの海流には永遠の流れがあるのです。
The sea water rising from the bottom of the sea has completely cooled this side
海底から湧き出た海水がこちら側をすっかり冷やしてしまいました
The sea temperature here is about three to five degrees lower.
ここの海水温は3〜5度ほど低いです
Much lower here even in his summer
ここでは夏でもずっと低い
why not here
ではなぜ無いのか
Ok this is our Homework for today
はい、これが今日の宿題です
Homework, please find the answer
宿題、答えを見つけてください
Why is there no one here, okay?
なぜここには誰もいないのですか？
ok i'm back here
わかりました、私はここに戻ってきました
Then my advisor wants to know why typhoons grow here
それから私のアドバイザーは、なぜここで台風が発生するのかを知りたがっています。
He has a theory, so he decides to test it out.
彼には理論があるので、それを試してみることにしました。
That's when the only typhoon grows
その時だけ台風が成長する
This place is still very close to mainland Mexico.
この場所はまだメキシコ本土に非常に近いです。
So we can take the plane to Mexico to detect the typhoon
それで台風を探知するためにメキシコ行きの飛行機に乗れるのです
Then it is difficult here because in the wild ocean
それから、ここは難しいです、なぜなら野生の海だからです
It's also very difficult here
ここも非常に難しいです
So, I just happened to be playing the role of volunteer
それで、たまたまボランティアの役割を果たしただけです
Just go to this event to answer this question
この質問に答えるためにこのイベントに行くだけです
Then our design is like this
それでは、私たちのデザインは次のようになります
This has a theory, you have to prove it
これには理論があるので、それを証明する必要があります
You should prove that you can only prove that the theory is wrong
理論が間違っていることしか証明できないことを証明すべきだ
You can't prove the theory is right
その理論が正しいことを証明することはできない
You can only testify whether your answer is positive
自分の答えが肯定的であるかどうかのみを証言できます
In fact, just supporting does not mean that the theory must be correct.
実際、単に支持するだけでは、その理論が正しい必要があるというわけではありません。
But if you can just find a different result, the theory is wrong.
しかし、異なる結果が見つかるだけであれば、その理論は間違っています。
There's a lot of cloud development here
ここではクラウド開発が盛んに行われています
We also flew into these clouds to see the typhoon with the Nichiri machine crossed by two planes.
私たちもこの雲の中に飛んで、ニチリ機と２機が横切る台風を見に行きました。
after reading it
それを読んだ後
You can bring back data to know that some of these clouds are missing
データを持ち帰って、これらのクラウドの一部が欠落していることを知ることができます
Some clouds turned into typhoons
一部の雲が台風に変わりました
Then you compare the specific characteristics of which clouds become typhoons
次に、どの雲が台風になるかの具体的な特徴を比較します。
Information on the physics of the atmosphere
大気の物理学に関する情報
to explain some theories
いくつかの理論を説明するために
Through this method we conduct experiments
この方法で実験を行っていきます
Then I happened to be very lucky to participate in this experiment and learned a lot at that time.
そして、私は幸運にもこの実験に参加することができ、その時に多くのことを学びました。
That
それか
Didn't this typhoon fly over a typhoon?
今回の台風は台風の上を飛んだんじゃないの？
This plane flies over a typhoon and will leave a typhoon mark
この飛行機は台風の上を飛行し、台風の跡を残します
What about this imprint?
この刻印はどうでしょうか？
By then he had 44
その時までに彼は44を持っていました
There are two imprints in it, please see
刻印が2つありますのでご覧ください
It grows in a different direction, these two
違う方向に伸びていく、この二つ
Why
なぜ
Because he once flew to the southern hemisphere
彼はかつて南半球に飛んだことがあるからです
The direction of the typhoon there is just anti-symmetrical to our northern hemisphere
そこの台風の進行方向は北半球とはちょうど反対称です
It was the first time in my life that I flew into a typhoon rock that developed from the rain slowly and slowly for three days
3日間ゆっくりと雨が降り続いて発達した台風の岩に飛び込んだのは生まれて初めてでした
So it's a rare life experience
だからそれは稀な人生経験だよ
but most importantly
しかし最も重要なことは
Participate in an experiment where students learn all research methods and tools for free
学生がすべての研究方法とツールを無料で学ぶ実験に参加します
Some attitudes or experiences when communicating with scientists are also good
科学者とコミュニケーションをとる際には、何らかの態度や経験を持つことも良いことです
Then when I got on the plane for the first time, I thought to myself
そして、初めて飛行機に乗ったとき、こう思いました。
Oh right, why is there no such thing as a flight attendant?
そうそう、なぜ客室乗務員というものが存在しないのですか？
In fact, it was all hard work by the technicians.
実際、それはすべて技術者たちの重労働でした。
It's all equipment
全て装備品です
i tied myself tight
私は自分をきつく縛りました
The first sentence is to ask those scientific and technical personnel to say
最初の文は、科学技術関係者に次のように言うことです。
Hey, why did you take off before taking a lecture?
おい、なぜ講義を受ける前に脱いでしまったんだ？
What about the safety lecture?
安全講習はどうですか？
He said
彼は言った
ah he just told me
ああ、彼は私に言ったばかりです
Don't worry
心配しないで
do not worry
心配しないでください
no problem
問題ない
not bad
悪くない
Because in the typhoon at sea
海上では台風なので
in case something goes wrong
何か問題が起こった場合に備えて
then accept fate
それから運命を受け入れる
But luckily everything went well
しかし幸運なことにすべてがうまくいきました
In fact, the United States from 1970 to the present
実際、1970 年から現在までの米国
There are so many planes that fly into the typhoon
台風に突っ込む飛行機がたくさんある
There is no record of any so-called casualties
いわゆる死傷者の記録はない
there may have been
あったかもしれない
no more after that
それ以降はもうダメ
Then if you have such experience
では、そのような経験をお持ちの方は
NOAA
NOAA
Also present you with a certificate
証明書もお渡しします
That's one of the baby in my life
それは私の人生の赤ちゃんの一人です
that's all
それで全部です
I believe that few people have the opportunity
チャンスがある人は少ないと思います
do such activities
そのような活動をする
I happen to own this one
私はたまたまこれを所有しています
He also wrote some very touching...
彼はまた、とても感動的なことを書いていました...
can't say touching
感動とは言えない
some encouraging words
いくつかの励ましの言葉
There is such a Mr. Wu
こんな呉さんがいるよ
deliberately on that day
あの日は意図的に
purposefully
意図的に
Where can I travel with my senseless spirit?
愚かな魂を持ってどこへ旅すればいいでしょうか？
Go inside the eyeball of some wicked typhoon in the West Indies
西インド諸島の邪悪な台風の目玉の中に入ってみましょう
This selfless orange and hero's devotion
無私のオレンジと英雄の献身
To us in science is to give him the highest tribute
私たち科学者に対して、彼に最高の敬意を表することです
oh thank you
ああ、ありがとう
sorry
ごめん
I just hinted that that wasn't intentional
それは意図的ではないことを示唆しただけです
good
良い
after i return to taiwan
台湾に帰ってから
Of course, a lot of basic research has been done
もちろん基礎研究もたくさん行われています
That research just now is not my doctoral thesis either.
今の研究も私の博士論文ではありません。
It's a process of my experience
それは私の経験のプロセスです
I just had a chance later
後でチャンスがあっただけ
I also find this question interesting
この質問も興味深いと思います
I'm going to share this with you in the last ten minutes
このことを最後の 10 分で皆さんと共有します
The experience of developing this scientific research
この科学研究を発展させた経験
If there are young friends here today,
もし今日ここに若い友達がいたら、
I also hope to have some inspiration
私も何かインスピレーションが得られれば幸いです
That is of course the process of learning
それはもちろん学習のプロセスです
learn a lot of different facets
多くのさまざまな側面を学ぶ
Then I just had this chance at last
そして、ついにこのチャンスが巡ってきたのです
It's time to let go and make a fortune
手放して富を築く時が来た
It just so happens that we put it together
たまたまそれを組み合わせただけです
Then I was nearly ten years ago
それから私は10年近く前でした
It's been ten years
10年経ちました
I organized it almost ten years ago
10年近く前に企画しました
such a new plan
そんな新しい企画
Hope NSC Hope Says
ホープ NSC ホープが語る
We have a focused study
私たちは集中的な研究を行っています
There is a relatively breakthrough development
比較的画期的な開発が行われている
I just come up with ideas that I might be able to do
自分にもできそうなアイデアを思いついただけです
I think we have an opportunity to do this kind of detection as well.
私たちにもこの種の検出を行う機会があると思います。
This project is me and a very good colleague
このプロジェクトは私ととても良い同僚です
made together
一緒に作った
So this job is actually a teamwork
つまり、この仕事は実際にはチームワークなのです
this is very important
これはとても重要です
It took me a lot of time to design this logo to popularize
このロゴをデザインして普及させるのにかなりの時間がかかりました
besides
そのほか
I've been thinking about this term for a month
私はこの言葉について一ヶ月間考えてきました
I made up the word DustStar
ダストスターという言葉は私が作りました
Of course it is meaningful when talking about typhoon observation
もちろん台風観測を語る上でも有意義です
It just so happens that this is dim sum
たまたまこれが点心です
DustStar
ダストスター
mentioned on my page
私のページに記載されている
like in the night sky of a typhoon
台風の夜空のように
Like the stars that lit up the night sky after we went to observe
観察に行ったら夜空を星のように照らした
just the intention
ただの意図
So our team is still doing well
だから私たちのチームはまだうまくいっている
DustStar
ダストスター
of course it's a joke
もちろん冗談だよ
Basically, when I visited the United States in 2007, I felt that the experiment was quite successful
基本的に、2007 年に米国を訪れたとき、この実験はかなり成功したと感じました。
Just google to find out that most of the ambassadors are famous
グーグルで調べれば、アンバサダーのほとんどが有名人であることがわかります。
It turned out to be a new British rock band.
それは新しいイギリスのロックバンドであることが判明しました。
But we also took a photo of him looking like this at the gate of National Taiwan University
でも、国立台湾大学の門でこんな顔の写真も撮りました。
big breath door
ビッグブレスドア
good
良い
what about our plan
私たちの計画はどうですか
Basically, we rented a jet plane from Hanxiang in Taichung to detect the typhoon
基本的に、台風を探知するために台中の漢翔からジェット機を借りました。
And this detection is strategic
そしてこの検出は戦略的です
We're going to find some places where the atmosphere is particularly sensitive to throw our heads
空気が特に危険な場所をいくつか見つけるつもりです
The instrument just mentioned
先ほど挙げた楽器
I hope this can change our understanding and prediction of typhoons
これによって台風に対する私たちの理解と予測が変わることを願っています
Then we did another job to measure the results
次に、結果を測定するために別の作業を行いました
Even if it is released to any research unit and forecast center in the world, it is not hidden at all
世界中のどの研究機関や予報センターに公開されても全く隠蔽されない
Some studies say that the observers use the data for two years before others can use it.
一部の研究では、観察者は他の人がデータを使用できるようになるまで 2 年間データを使用すると述べています。
Because of the typhoon
台風のせいで
So this impact is comprehensive and immediate
したがって、この影響は広範囲かつ即時的です
It's a pity to keep it for my own use
自分用に保管しておくのは残念です
That's also because we share it on the instant
それもインスタントで共有しているからです
We compile the data in the air and pass it on
データを編集して空に飛ばし、伝えます
So it can be taken back to WMO all over the world
したがって、世界中のWMOに持ち帰ることができます
all used countries
すべての使用国
Then maybe our back helmet will be bigger
そうすれば、後ろのヘルメットも大きくなるかもしれません
Then it faces many problems
その後、多くの問題に直面します
Then I may have an opportunity to introduce this to you later.
それでは、また後ほどご紹介する機会があるかもしれません。
In the blink of an eye, more than nine years have passed
あっという間に9年以上が経ちました
We have detected many, many typhoons
たくさんの台風を発見しました
And most of these typhoons have affected Taiwan
そしてこれらの台風のほとんどは台湾に影響を与えています
and even the surrounding countries
そして周囲の国さえも
Everyone can see that this door is all about us in the air
このドアが空中にいる私たちのすべてであることは誰でもわかります
Traces of every instrument ever dropped
これまでに落下したあらゆる器具の痕跡
Typhoon passing by
台風が通過中
So all the measuring instruments we've lost so far
これまでに失ったすべての測定器
nearly a thousand lost
千人近くが失われた
So it's a really big research effort
それは本当に大規模な研究努力です
ongoing
継続中
Of course, there are also a lot of research rumors
もちろん、研究の噂もたくさんあります
I'll show you some pictures
写真をいくつかお見せします
Aren't we always comparing this movement in the air
私たちはいつもこの空中の動きを比べていないでしょうか
This is exactly one of them
これはまさにその中の1つです
The whole design of our BNFAY is in the Central Meteorological Bureau
私たちのBNFAYの設計全体は中央気象局にあります
if you know how to get on the web
ウェブにアクセスする方法を知っている場合
You can see where our planes go
私たちの飛行機がどこへ行くのかがわかります
Then measure what data
では、どのようなデータを測定するか
Similar to the original satellite and radar pictures
元の衛星写真とレーダー写真に類似
all will be combined
すべてが結合されます
It's all on the Bureau of Meteorology's webpage
すべては気象庁のウェブページに載っています
immediately visible
すぐに見える
But there is a specific URL that is
ただし、特定の URL があります。
Not everyone can find it
誰もが見つけられるわけではない
This information will be available to anyone who can find it
この情報は、見つけられる人なら誰でも見ることができます
The Central Weather Service in their combined
中央気象局はそれらを組み合わせた
all the different sources of observation
さまざまな観察源すべて
Information about our aircraft
当社の航空機に関する情報
He can study and judge the original characteristics of the typhoon
彼は台風の本来の性質を研究し判断することができる
Of course, this is only the so-called application part
もちろん、これはいわゆるアプリケーション部分にすぎません
Our research is like my example
私たちの研究は私の例のようなものです
We call it target observation
私たちはそれを目標観測と呼んでいます
like the so-called target
いわゆるターゲットのようなもの
A treatment like chemotherapy
化学療法のような治療法
This is called targeted therapy
これは標的療法と呼ばれます
Our method is called targeted observation
私たちの方法は標的観察と呼ばれます
to measure
測定する
The most famous example is not a paper I wrote
最も有名な例は私が書いた論文ではありません
It was made by the Japanese who worked with us
私たちと一緒に働いていた日本人が作ったものです
In this example inside
この例では内部
We went to measure various data of this typhoon
今回の台風の各種データを計測しに行ってきました
Three of these are targets
このうち3名が対象です
As a result we found
その結果、私たちが見つけたのは、
Japanese found
日本人発見
Prediction of typhoon direction by the weather model of the whole Japan
日本全国の気象モデルによる台風の進路予測
this is the actual direction
これが実際の方向です
After using this data
このデータを使用した後
Typhoon will turn around
台風が向きを変える
if not
そうでない場合
The typhoon will come here in the wrong direction
台風は間違った方向からここに来るでしょう
that this one
これは
The results of this study probably helped us gain popularity
この研究の結果はおそらく私たちの人気を高めるのに役立ったでしょう
Then I quote a movie I watched before called
それから私は前に見た映画を引用します。
Oh, this one is called honey, there seems to be this movie
ああ、これはハニーと呼ばれるものです、この映画があるようです
I made the kid bigger or smaller
私は子供を大きくしたり小さくしたりしました
We turned the typhoon
私たちは台風を変えた
Of course it means that we take the typhoon forecast
もちろん台風予報を参考にするということです
The prediction turned out to be in the direction he should go
その予言は彼の進むべき方向に当たった
After nearly many years of research
ほぼ何年にもわたる研究を経て
We found that on average we can reduce the error by about 20%
平均して誤差を約 20% 削減できることがわかりました。
That is to say, the original error may predict the position of the typhoon one day later
つまり、元の誤差は 1 日後の台風の位置を予測する可能性があります。
There may be an average error of 100 kilometers between the present and the actual situation
現在と実際の状況には平均100キロメートルの誤差がある可能性があります
It can become only 80 kilometers left
残り80キロになるかも知れません
not perfect
完璧ではない
Because the atmosphere is not perfectly predictable.
なぜなら、雰囲気は完全に予測できるものではないからです。
However, there are possibilities and results for improvement after the information is available
ただし、情報が入手可能になった後は改善の可能性と結果が得られます。
In 2008 we succeeded because of this
2008 年に私たちはこのおかげで成功しました
The whole of Asia has started a new experiment
アジア全体が新たな実験を始めた
This experiment is through our aircraft
この実験は私たちの航空機を使って行われます
Like inviting the United States to bring two large planes
米国に大型飛行機２機を連れてくるよう誘うようなものだ
And Japan also came to fly all the typhoons with a plane
そして日本にはあらゆる台風を飛ばすための飛行機もある
So we cross explored
そこで私たちは相互に調査しました
At that time, it was equal to the typhoon in the Northwest Pacific in 2008
当時は2008年の北西太平洋の台風に匹敵した
what to explore
何を探索するか
The life and death of the whole typhoon
台風全体の生と死
how did it grow
どのように成長しましたか
How did it dissipate in the end
結局どうやって消えたのか
All in this experiment want to answer
この実験に参加している全員が答えを求めています
It's never been done before with a test flight
試験飛行ではこれまでに行われたことがありません
Of course it will require a lot of cooperation
もちろん多大な協力が必要ですが
We can imagine test piloting planes flying together in the sky
テストパイロットの飛行機が空を一緒に飛んでいる様子が想像できます
The planes all depart from different countries
飛行機はすべて異なる国から出発します
stagger together at last
ついに一緒によろめきます
it's all designed
それはすべて設計されたものです
Of course it is impossible to collide
もちろん衝突することはありません
that this team
このチームが
It is developed under the framework of the whole WMO
WMO全体の枠組みのもとで開発されている
There are representatives from various countries
色々な国の代表がいます
There is a country called Dustar
ダスターという国がある
Sorry can't use the name Taiwan
申し訳ありませんが、台湾という名前は使用できません
What about after we do this?
これを行った後はどうでしょうか？
There was a famous example
有名な例がありました
Xinleke Typhoon
シンレケ・タイフーン
First time in the Pacific Northwest
太平洋岸北西部では初めて
with our planes flying around like this
私たちの飛行機がこうやって飛び回っています
I'm on this plane
私はこの飛行機に乗っています
Then the US plane flew from Guam
その後、米軍機がグアムから飛来
There is another plane from the United States flying over.
上空をアメリカからの別の飛行機が飛んでいます。
Japanese planes fly over from Tokyo's Atsuki Airport
東京の厚木空港から日本の航空機が飛来
the military airport
軍用空港
Then go around here and go back, stop at the airport in Okinawa
それからこの辺を回って戻って、沖縄の空港に立ち寄ります。
Test pilots fly together for the first time in the Pacific Northwest
テストパイロットが初めて太平洋岸北西部で一緒に飛行
I showed you the simplest example
最も単純な例を示しました
This paper has also been published
こんな論文も出版されています
Our observations show
私たちの観察によると、
If there is this information
この情報があれば
The typhoon will turn this way, close to the typhoon
台風はこっちに曲がります、台風に近づきます
The computer will predict that the blue line is very close to the actual red line
コンピューターは、青い線が実際の赤い線に非常に近いと予測します。
Forecast from this time
今回からの予想
What if we don't use these observations?
これらの観察結果を使用しない場合はどうなるでしょうか?
it will be green, it's wrong
それは緑色になります、それは間違っています
It's the same here, it's a day later
ここでも同じです、一日後です
Then this photo is
じゃあこの写真は
We always remember to leave a photo before every flight
私たちはフライト前に必ず写真を残すことを忘れないでください
As a souvenir
お土産として
Then the In case newspaper needs to be used the next day
翌日新聞を使用する必要がある場合に備えて
But it's not used yet
でもまだ使われてないよ
In theory, it was a very sweet year.
理論的には、今年は非常に良い年でした。
That National Geographic
あのナショナルジオグラフィック
Just made a documentary about our story
私たちの物語についてのドキュメンタリーを制作しました
In the next year, 2001, every two years
翌2001年からは2年ごとに
That is, two years ago we got another one
つまり、2年前に別のものを入手しました
Another larger international experiment was organized
別の大規模な国際実験が組織されました
This is cooperation with Taiwan's marine community
これは台湾の海洋コミュニティとの協力です
we still fly
私たちはまだ飛んでいます
This cooperation was just mentioned to you
この協力については先ほど触れたばかりです
we're going to explore the ocean
私たちは海を探検するつもりです
Both the atmosphere and the ocean
大気も海も
So our domestic and foreign oceans
つまり、私たちの国内外の海は、
Ships go to sea to detect
船は探知するために海に出ます
It must have the detection instruments of this ocean
この海の探知装置を備えているに違いない
Still have to go below 100 meters
まだ100メートル以下に行かなければなりません
The thermal structure of the ocean
海洋の熱構造
Structure of Temperature Structure of Density
温度の構造 密度の構造
See how it changes before and after the typhoon
台風の前後でどう変わるか見てみましょう
To understand how much the ocean is affected by typhoons
台風による海への影響を知る
and how much it affects the subsequent development of the typhoon
台風のその後の発達にどれだけ影響するか
The result you see is like this photo
表示される結果はこの写真のようになります
we made a
私たちはを作りました
very interesting surround
とても興味深いサラウンド
American planes fly in it
アメリカの飛行機が飛んでます
We still need to use the phone in the air
まだ空中で電話を使う必要がある
connect with computer
コンピュータに接続する
in contact with each other
互いに連絡を取り合っている
Because they don't want us to fly higher
彼らは私たちがより高く飛ぶことを望んでいないからです
about 13 kilometers
約13キロ
They fly at an altitude of only about 4 kilometers to 5 kilometers
高度はわずか4キロから5キロ程度で飛行します。
They don't want us flying over their heads
彼らは私たちが頭上を飛んでいくのを望んでいない
just drop things
ただ何かを落とすだけ
Although the chances of hitting are very, very low
当たる確率はかなり低いですが、
But they still hope not
しかし彼らはまだそうならないことを望んでいる
it's all planned
それはすべて計画されています
This study is actually quite interesting
この研究は実際非常に興味深いものです
So in 2004
それで2004年に
In fact we're only doing it for the second year
実はまだ2年目しかやってないんです
The news bureau made this an interesting topic
報道局がこれを興味深い話題にしました
as in
のように
It is tantamount to promoting the development of Taiwan's technology
台湾の技術開発を促進することに等しい
this issue
この問題
Coincidentally, I got one
偶然にも１つ頂きました
Introduced Award
紹介賞
It shouldn't have anything to do with the hero
主人公とは関係ないはず
The director is too strong
監督強すぎる
But more memorable
でももっと思い出深いのは
Later, a documentary
その後、ドキュメンタリー
This is the National Geographic Channel
これはナショナル ジオグラフィック チャンネルです
he followed me
彼は私についてきました
The process of doing this task in 2008
2008 年にこのタスクを実行するプロセス
I have a few copies of this documentary
私はこのドキュメンタリーを何冊か持っています
Our DVD if interested students today especially
特に今日の学生に興味があるなら、私たちのDVD
If you are interested or children
興味のある方やお子様連れの方は
I'm happy to share
喜んで共有します
Of course there are many rare photos in the air
もちろんレアな写真も多数公開中
Everyone can see that if you are not in the sky, you can see a typhoon in your lower field of vision
空にいなくても、視界の下の方に台風が見えるのは誰でもわかります。
In fact, if mentioned at the beginning
実は、冒頭でも触れましたが、
This is a beautiful scientific study
これは素晴らしい科学的研究です
But of course it has its challenges
しかし、もちろん課題もあります
because as a presenter
なぜならプレゼンターとして
We have a great responsibility to make sure
私たちにはそれを確認する大きな責任があります
The whole process is safe
プロセス全体が安全です
And of course we were able to do this research mainly because of government funding.
そしてもちろん、私たちがこの研究を行うことができたのは主に政府の資金提供によるものです。
So be very careful
だから十分気をつけてね
Hope to achieve what we should do
やるべきことを達成したい
over the past ten years
過去10年間にわたって
Probably all the relevant research I have been engaged in is in this field.
おそらく、私がこれまで携わってきた関連研究はすべてこの分野のものです。
Trying to answer questions about different aspects of the typhoon
台風のさまざまな側面についての質問に答えようとしています
Hope to find an updated answer
最新の答えが見つかることを願っています
I was lucky enough to find some results
幸運にもいくつかの結果を見つけることができました
Well, of course I'm on this plane today.
さて、今日はもちろんこの飛行機に乗ります。
Introduced to you about the strategic measurement part
戦略計測パートについてご紹介しました
As I introduced at the beginning today
今日は冒頭でも紹介したように
Typhoon measurement has many different aspects
台風の測定にはさまざまな側面があります
In fact, it is still under development
実はまだ開発中です
and we're still working on it
そして私たちはまだそれに取り組んでいます
Maybe there will be more opportunities in the future
もしかしたら今後もチャンスが増えるかも知れません
Let me introduce more results
詳しい結果をご紹介します
Of course it's a Vision
もちろんビジョンです
That is to say, in fact there needs to be one more
つまり、実際にはもう 1 つ必要です
good scientists and researchers to participate
優れた科学者や研究者が参加する
In order to bring this research to a higher level
この研究をより高いレベルに引き上げるために
And it can solve the problems of science and people's livelihood
そして科学と人々の生活の問題を解決できる
Well I guess it's one of our visions
まあ、それは私たちのビジョンの一つだと思います
then let me introduce to you
それでは紹介させてください
what chance is there in the future
将来的にはどのような可能性がありますか
In the United States, they have figured out a way to update
米国では、アップデートする方法を見つけ出しました。
to replace the existing aircraft
既存の航空機を置き換える
They use this very famous one called Global Hawk
彼らはグローバルホークと呼ばれるこの非常に有名なものを使用しています
Unmanned aircraft called Voice of the Sky
無人航空機「Voice of the Sky」
this plane is a reconnaissance plane
この飛行機は偵察機です
was used in the Iraq war to detect
イラク戦争では探知のために使用された
The so-called important key tool of where the enemy is
敵がどこにいるかを知る、いわゆる重要なキーツール
The other plane is called the Predator
もう一方の飛行機はプレデターと呼ばれます
Just go fire the missiles, you probably know
ミサイルを発射してください、おそらく知っています
This drone just happens to have a few
このドローンはたまたまいくつか持っています
Americans came up with an idea
アメリカ人がアイデアを思いついた
Donate to NASA Donate to NASA from the Department of Defense
NASAに寄付 国防総省からNASAに寄付
NASA is going to use this plane to detect
NASAはこの飛行機を使って探知する予定です
First target to detect typhoon
台風を探知する最初の目標
This experiment has been carried out
この実験は行われました
currently flying
現在飛行中
The plan for this experiment is well organized
この実験の計画はよく練られている
just a good friend of mine
ただの私の良い友達です
Here's a photo of him standing on this Global retreat
これがこのグローバル・リトリートに立っている彼の写真です
they will
彼らはそうするだろう
I've been experimenting with this aircraft since about last year
私は去年くらいからこの飛行機を実験してきました
This Plane Flies Higher Unmanned Aircraft
この飛行機はより高く飛ぶ 無人航空機
Fly at an altitude of 18 kilometers
高度18キロメートルを飛行
above the typhoon
台風の上に
So he is less affected by the typhoon
だから彼は台風の影響をあまり受けない
And he can fly for a long time at a time
そして一度に長時間飛行できる
There are a few days so you can constantly monitor the typhoon
数日あるので常に台風を監視できる
The organizer happened to be at the beginning of June
主催者はたまたま6月の初めに来ました
Almost two months ago, I visited Taiwan
私は約2か月前に台湾を訪れました
Then I was also discussing with him whether they should consider
それから私も彼と検討すべきかどうか話し合っていました。
Fly this aircraft to the Pacific Northwest to try it out
この飛行機に乗って太平洋岸北西部まで飛ばして試してみましょう
But we're now waiting for their results in the Atlantic
しかし、私たちは今、大西洋での結果を待っています。
if this goes well
これがうまくいけば
Maybe this will be the mainstream of typhoon observation around the world in the future
もしかしたらこれが今後の世界の台風観測の主流になるかもしれません
Of course this plane is very expensive
もちろんこの飛行機はとても高価です
Fortunately, the aircraft donated to them by the Ministry of National Defense of the country are doing such detection
幸いなことに、国防省から寄贈された航空機はそのような探知を行っています。
May change our future study of typhoons
今後の台風研究が変わるかもしれない
Instead of various observation tools
各種観察ツールの代わりに
And this Gu Liang without any staff is safe Gu Liang
そして、スタッフのいないこの古良は安全です。
The last story is to tell you about the past 10 years
最後のお話はこの10年間をお話します
I travel all over the world like this
こうやって世界中を旅してるんだ
Every point is a place I've been
あらゆる点が私が行ったことのある場所です
So as a scientist
だから科学者として
can be regarded as a person
人とみなされることができる
a variety of experiences
さまざまな経験
We go to various places to meet and do experiments
いろんなところに行って打ち合わせしたり実験したりしてます
to learn new things
新しいことを学ぶために
Then I just talked about 2002
それから私は 2002 年のことについて話しました
i was there once
私は一度そこにいました
What about the typhoon seminar held by the World Meteorological Organization of the United Nations every four years?
国連の世界気象機関が4年に一度開催する台風セミナーはどうでしょうか？
every Quadrennial
四年一次
2002 to CANES
2002年からケインズへ
I just happened to experience my first dive in my life
たまたま人生初のダイビングを体験しました
then the scientist
それから科学者
this scientist is very famous
この科学者はとても有名です
Just happened to go diving with me
たまたま一緒に海に潜っただけです
just the two of us
私達二人だけ
Just then we each had a baby
ちょうどそのとき、私たちそれぞれに赤ちゃんが生まれました
So we hugged a CQCumbers sea cucumber each
そこで私たちはCQCumbersのナマコをそれぞれ抱きしめました
It's like a baby passport
赤ちゃんのパスポートのようなものです
As a result, I now have a very good research understanding and cooperation with him.
その結果、私は今では彼と研究に対する非常に良い理解と協力関係を築いています。
Maybe it's all because we once lived together under the sea
それはきっと、かつて海の底で一緒に暮らしていたからかもしれない
The other one I just talked about
もう一つは先ほどお話しした
We also went to Costoreca for the once-in-a-decade meeting of the World Meteorological Organization
私たちは世界気象機関の10年に一度の会議のためにコストレカにも行きました。
I came to this place two years ago
2年前にこの場所に来ました
No one ever knows where to go
どこに行くべきか誰も知りません
Call Lara Union on Liu Niwang Island
劉尼王島のララユニオンに電話する
in the indian ocean
インド洋で
south indian ocean
南インド洋
very nice beach
とても素敵なビーチ
Like this is not the same as Su this
これはSuと同じではないように、これは
These so-called
これらのいわゆる
This place in the prefecture of Mar
マール県のこの場所
world famous
世界知名的
then we just went to a meeting
それから私たちはちょうど会議に行ったところです
I'm just talking and doing research
ただ話したり調べたりしているだけです
Actually there are many interesting parts
実は面白い部分がたくさんあるんです
There are many people who are doing and are pursuing life
人生をやり遂げ、追求している人がたくさんいます
direction of young friends
若い友達の方向性
Maybe we can join this ranks in the future
もしかしたら将来的にはこの仲間入りをするかもしれない
I'm lucky enough to say
言えるのは幸運だ
I just happened to quote this Steve Jobs
たまたまスティーブ・ジョブズの言葉を引用しました
at Stanford University in 2005
2005年にスタンフォード大学で
The content of this Speech
このスピーチの内容
Although he is unfortunate
彼は不幸ではあるが
he has passed away
彼は亡くなりました
But he talked about it a few years ago
しかし、彼は数年前にそれについて話しました
life is about connecting this
人生とはこれを繋ぐことだ
a lot of bits and pieces
たくさんの断片
I saw this DUTZ
このDUTZを見ました
It can be combined with my DUTZ DUTZ quite well
私のDUTZ DUTZとうまく組み合わせることができます
Then I think I'm very lucky too
それなら私もとても幸運だと思います
Take what you have learned in the past
過去に学んだことを活かして
shine up
輝ける
So right now at this
それで今この時点で
very special
とても特別な
Research areas continue to evolve
研究分野は進化し続ける
Okay, what about yesterday? Today Vice President Peng mentioned
さて、昨日はどうですか? 今日は彭副総統が次のように述べました。
We flew to the typhoon
私たちは台風に向かって飛んだ
You can see we did a probe
私たちが調査を行ったことがわかります
This information is placed on the website
この情報はウェブサイトに掲載されています
This typhoon is still developing
この台風はまだ発達中です
But I can't say much under the meteorological law.
しかし、気象法上は何とも言えません。
But I think this typhoon may still be very threatening
しかし、この台風はまだ非常に脅威である可能性があると思います
or please pay more attention
またはもっと注意してください
I was going to share a video
動画をシェアするつもりだったんだけど
But let's put this short story of ours
でも、私たちのこの短い物語を載せましょう
Also made a song and video
曲や動画も作りました
It was made by a college student of mine
うちの大学生が作ったものです
I made it into a MV
MVにしてみました
But this allows interested colleagues to perhaps go
しかし、これにより、興味のある同僚がおそらく行くことができます
Find the answer of Fengshou and you will see
鳳翔の答えを見つければわかります
The last thing I want to tell you is
最後に伝えたいことは、
This study is actually very lucky
この研究は実際には非常に幸運です
It's because government funding gives us the opportunity to do
それは政府の資金援助が私たちに機会を与えてくれるからです。
so i want to thank many people
だからたくさんの人に感謝したいです
that's like thank god
それは神に感謝するようなものです
Taiwanese kids are very smart
台湾の子供たちはとても賢い
I heard that there is still this composition
この構図が今も残っていると聞きました
of course it was a joke
もちろん冗談だった
yes
はい
the last thing i want to say is
最後に言いたいのは
Thank you very much for the invitation of Academia Sinica
中央研究院のご招待誠にありがとうございます
Let everyone come together enthusiastically on the night of the typhoon
台風の夜はみんなで元気に集いましょう
Listen to me share our research abroad and experience
私たちの海外での研究と経験を共有するのを聞いてください
look forward to seeing you again
またお会いできるのを楽しみにしています
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thank you Director Wu for your wonderful speech
ウー監督、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとう
From very simple to cutting-edge research
非常にシンプルな研究から最先端の研究まで
I'm the moderator and I usually control the time
私は司会者で、通常は時間をコントロールします
So I hope it's 9 o'clock to let everyone go
だから9時になったらみんなを帰せるといいのですが
12 minutes left now
あと 12 分
protection time
保護時間
quick to ask questions
すぐに質問する
OK
OK
ok thank you for a very good presentation
わかりました、とても良いプレゼンテーションをありがとう
From what you just said, it seems
今言ったことからすると、どうやら
The information of the ocean
海の情報
very predictive
非常に予測的
So maybe in the future the big breath will combine with the ocean
だから将来的には大きな息が海と結合するかもしれない
i'm kidding
冗談です
My question is actually
私の質問は実は
Unlike the surveillance in the air
空中監視とは異なります
You can fly through it quickly
すぐに飛び越えることができる
Then in the ocean when you have to do both sides
それから海では両側をやらなければならないとき
Do you want to put a lot of ships?
船をたくさん入れたいですか？
or is there anything massive
それとも何か巨大なものがあるのか
There can also be a monitoring method for sentient beings who go Z
Z状態の知覚存在を監視する方法もあり得る
Thank you for this very good question
とても良い質問をありがとう
The first suggestion you just made
あなたが行った最初の提案
It's actually very, very important
実はとてもとても重要なことなのです
In fact, many atmospheres and oceans abroad
実は海外の大気や海はたくさんあります。
is the same technology
同じ技術です
Of course, there may be more appropriate and mature opportunities in China.
もちろん、中国にはより適切で成熟した機会があるかもしれません。
should develop in that direction
その方向に発展するべきだ
What about observations at sea?
海上での観測はどうでしょうか？
It's really difficult
的確比較困難
This is why ocean observations are not as rich as the atmosphere
海洋観測が大気ほど豊かではないのはこのためです
the ocean
海
Each of your probes is actually very expensive
それぞれのプローブは実際には非常に高価です
If you want to detect the phone before and after the typhoon
台風の前後に電話を検知したい場合
it also has a lot of risk
それは多くのリスクも伴います
Because it can't get close don't say typhoon
近づけないから台風なんて言わないで
any let big to a degree
ある程度大きくしても構いません
can't get close anyway
とにかく近づけない
So if their design is to go through this kind of research
したがって、彼らのデザインがこの種の研究を経ることになる場合、
At that time, the detection of the iTOP experiment just now
その時、先程のiTOP実験の検知
it requires making very rigorous forecasts of our atmosphere
大気を非常に厳密に予測する必要がある
To create a typhoon, go there
台風を起こすにはそこに行きなさい
Then it has to be 2 to 3 days before the typhoon goes in that direction
となると、台風がその方向に進むまでには2～3日かかるはずです
The ship is already going to that location to arrange various detection camps.
船はすでにその場所に向かい、さまざまな探知キャンプを準備しています。
Then they will flash
すると点滅します
Then wait for the typhoon to pass
あとは台風が過ぎるのを待ちます
So it's a little bit of a part like fishing
だからそれは釣りのような小さな部分です
Then if the typhoon doesn't go to those materials in the end
それで結局台風がその材料のところに行かなかったら
still cold
まだ寒い
But there is no way to cool enough to see the information
でも情報を見るほど冷静になる方法はない
So currently is progress in this situation
現在、この状況は進展しています
However, in these major international experiments
しかし、こうした大規模な国際実験では、
It usually arranges more points just to ask for safety
通常は安全を求めるためだけに、より多くのポイントを配置します
A web of data connected in one line
1 本の線でつながったデータの網
Let the typhoon cool down to the surrounding area no matter where the typhoon passes
台風がどこを通過しても周囲に涼しさを与えましょう
Especially what happened to the seabed before the typhoon passed by
特に台風が通過する前に海底はどうなったのか
What does the bottom of the sea look like when you pass by
近くを通ると海の底はどうなっているでしょうか？
If it's all cold enough, there will be results.
十分に冷えていれば結果は出ます。
that result
その結果
This food test was completed almost two years ago.
この食品検査はほぼ 2 年前に完了しました。
At present, many scientists are paying attention to this research work
現在、多くの科学者がこの研究成果に注目しています。
so very avant-garde
とても前衛的な
And there should be many new results to introduce in the future
そして、将来的には多くの新しい成果が紹介されるはずです
I did not talk about the results of this part of the results today
今日はこの部分の結果については話しませんでした
If a large area grain survey is to be done
広範囲の穀物調査を行う場合
possible over the ocean
海を越えても可能
Yes, the ocean now has some automatic instruments too
はい、海にも自動計器がいくつかあります
But what is the purpose of its grain testing?
しかし、穀物検査の目的は何でしょうか?
I might say for example
たとえば、こう言うかもしれません
I have some now with a grain measuring instrument called the Argo
私は今、Argo という穀物測定器を使っていくつか持っています。
This instrument is very interesting
この楽器はとても面白いです
The world has now deployed thousands of different seas around the world
世界は現在、世界中に何千もの異なる海を展開しています。
But its disadvantage is that it has no faults
しかし、欠点は欠点がないことです
so it floats
だから浮く
so you don't ignore where it is
だからあなたはそれがどこにあるのか無視しないでください
finally
ついに
over a period of time
一定期間にわたって
All will float to the shore
みんな岸に浮かんでいくだろう
There is no way to stay where you want at sea
海上では好きな場所に留まることができない
I have no choice but to let it go
もう手放すしかない
what about it
それはどうですか
it will be because of the sunshine every day
毎日の太陽のせいだろう
it will have some density change
多少の密度変化はあるでしょう
it will sink into the sea
それは海に沈んでしまいます
then measure
それから測定します
Then time, a certain time, it floats up again
そして時が経つとまた浮かんでくる
When it floated up, it measured the entire vertical data again.
浮き上がったところで再度垂直全体のデータを計測しました。
then when it floats up
それから浮き上がったら
Its antenna can receive satellite signals
アンテナは衛星信号を受信できます
It can transmit data to the satellite
衛星にデータを送信できる
There is such a measure to pass the data out
データを渡すにはそのような措置があります
So different scientists are indeed designing
実際、さまざまな科学者が設計を行っています
Different measuring instruments help us solve
さまざまな測定器が解決に役立ちます
This is not a problem that ships can solve
これは船が解決できる問題ではありません
it can use a ship to deploy this instrument
この機器を配備するために船を使用することができます
then let it walk on the sea
それから海の上を歩かせてください
Then you can measure a lot
そうすればたくさん測定できるよ
There are ups and downs to measure the data
データの測定には浮き沈みがある
The more active approach in our experiment is
私たちの実験におけるより積極的なアプローチは、
fly by plane
飛行機で飛ぶ
Because the ship is sometimes slow, there is a risk
船が遅い場合もあるので危険があります
Fly near the typhoon by plane
飛行機で台風の近くを飛ぶ
From the plane, the plane has to fly lower
飛行機から見ると、飛行機はより低く飛行しなければなりません
Probably can only fly at an altitude of 1000 meters or 300 meters
おそらく高度1000メートルか300メートルでしか飛べない
Under those conditions, drop the instrument
このような状況では、機器を落としてください。
After that instrument was thrown into the sea,
その楽器が海に投げ込まれた後、
The ocean's instruments will dive down to detect
海の機器は探知するために潜ります
What about a few days later?
数日後はどうでしょうか？
It will be recycled than
以上よりリサイクルされます
because it is very expensive compared to
に比べて非常に高価であるため、
Then it can also be detected
そうすれば検出もできる
But this whole design
しかし、このデザイン全体
Requires a lot of technology including engineering
エンジニアリングを含む多くの技術が必要です
But everyone is developing
でもみんな成長してるよ
especially in
特に
Some advanced countries like the United States have
アメリカのような一部の先進国では、
It's good that this kind of facility is doing this kind of research work
このような施設でこのような研究が行われているのは素晴らしいことです
Then our domestic marine community also has related issues.
国内の海洋コミュニティも関連する問題を抱えています。
nice
良い
some research like this
このような研究もあります
some experience
いくつかの経験
So I did this international cooperation just now
それで私は今この国際協力をしました
good
良い
That is
あれは
good last man
良い最後の男
use that microphone
そのマイクを使ってください
ok
Ok
that's in
それは入っています
Forecasting the Taiwan in the Taiwan area
台湾で台湾を予測する
It seems that Taiwan is doing
台湾もやってるらしい
Japan is also doing
日本もやってるよ
America is doing
アメリカはやってる
The information on the seven items seems to be
7つの項目の情報は次のようです。
Countries are exchanging
各国が交流している
But often that predicts
しかし、多くの場合、それは予測されます
like
好き
Every country will be different
国ごとに違うだろう
where is the reason
理由はどこにありますか
that Taiwan
あの台湾
In the forecast near Taiwan
台湾付近の予報では
Taiwan's path when
台湾の進路
Does Taiwan have any advantages?
台湾には何かメリットがあるのでしょうか？
The second one is that it seems that in the past few years
2つ目は、ここ数年で
The Taiwan that passed the seventh place in Taiwan seems to be smaller than the average number
台湾7位通過の台湾は平均数より少ない模様
Then it seems that the chance to hear the strong Taiwan seems to be relatively small
となると、強い台湾を聞く機会は比較的少なそうです
what is the reason
理由は何ですか
Nanakka may be due to loading
ナナカは読み込みのせいかもしれない
But I feel that the number will be relatively small
でもその数は比較的少ない気がする
It seems to be different from the statistic of a writer you mentioned just now
先ほどの作家の統計とは違うようです
don't know how
方法がわかりません
Okay, let me answer the second question first
さて、まず 2 番目の質問に答えましょう
In fact, just now you mentioned whether it was some typhoon activity
実は、先ほど、台風の影響ではないかとおっしゃいました。
The frequency or intensity or character of passing through Taiwan
台湾を通過する頻度、強度、または特徴
Have there been any statistically significant changes over the past few years
過去数年間に統計的に有意な変化はありましたか
In fact, the typhoon has a certain variation in nature.
実際、台風は本質的に自然界で突然変異を起こします。
Then there's some variability from year to year
あとは年によって多少の変動はありますが、
So if you look at the very short angle
それで、非常に短い角度で見ると、
The significance of this statistic is not necessarily very special.
この統計の重要性は必ずしも特別なものではありません。
In other words, we don't really know yet
言い換えれば、まだ本当のことは分かっていない
Is there such a noticeable change
そんなに目立った変化あるのかな
That some need you to strengthen some of these points
これらの点のいくつかを強化する必要がある人もいるということ
More precise statistics may be needed
より正確な統計が必要な場合があります
we just know
私たちはただ知っています
But it is clear that scientists
しかし、科学者たちが
actually really understand
実は本当に理解しています
For example, we are in the tropical ocean
たとえば、私たちは熱帯の海の中にいるとします。
There will be a so-called holy cause
いわゆる聖なる大義があるだろう
sea ​​temperature will change
海水温が変わります
While these changes happen every few years
こうした変化は数年ごとに起こりますが、
Typhoon Occurrence Area
台風発生地域
with some of its activities indeed
実際、その活動の一部では
will change
変更されます
We already know more about these
これらについてはすでに詳しく知っています
That's for a place close to Taiwan
それは台湾に近い場所です
partial change
一部変更
In fact our statistics
実際、私たちの統計では
relatively without an obvious age
比較的年齢が明らかではない
or change over the years
または年月の経過とともに変化する
We are less clear about this
これについてはあまり明確ではありません
The other one needs more research
もう 1 つはさらに研究が必要です
So back to the question you asked at the beginning
それでは、最初の質問に戻りますが、
What are the forecasts for each country?
各国の予想はどうなるのでしょうか？
Meteorological data from all over the world
世界中の気象データ
under the framework of WMO
WMOの枠組みの下で
on the World Meteorological Organization
世界気象機関について
is fully opened
全開です
So people all over the world can make predictions
世界中の人々が予測できるようになる
The so-called official meteorological units of each country
いわゆる各国の公式気象単位
But each country has its own computer model
しかし、各国には独自のコンピューターモデルがあります
So it doesn't predict exactly the same
したがって、まったく同じことを予測するわけではありません
This is because of the design of the schema
これはスキーマの設計によるものです
How to enter the computer mode with its data
データを使用してコンピュータモードに入る方法
different answers will be different
違う答えは違うだろう
Then sometimes everyone's results are the same
そうすると、全員の結果が同じになることもあります
when this happens
これが起こるとき
This typhoon is likely to be well controlled
今回の台風はうまく制御されそうです
But when everyone is quite different
でもみんなが全く違うとき
It highlights that the typhoon has relatively high uncertainty.
台風の不確実性が比較的高いことが浮き彫りになった。
At the end of the day, every country has to make human judgments
結局のところ、どの国も人間の判断を下さなければなりません
The result may vary
結果は異なる場合があります
So what special so-called advantage does Taiwan have?
それでは、台湾にはどのような特別ないわゆる利点があるのでしょうか?
or advantage
または利点
Basically, when the typhoon is very close to Taiwan
基本的に、台風が台湾に非常に接近したとき
Usually the location of the typhoon we do in Taiwan
通常、台湾で行う台風のロケ地
and analysis of its nearby movement
そしてその近くの動きの分析
will be more accurate than other countries
他の国よりも正確になるでしょう
because it affects
影響するから
So our input will compare
したがって、私たちの入力は比較されます
Compared with the so-called extra manpower
いわゆる余剰人員と比べて
For example, he is also concerned about Japan
例えば、彼は日本のことも心配している
But because he is not comfortable in his country
しかし、彼は自分の国では快適ではないので、
He's just following normal procedures
彼は通常の手順に従っているだけです
so there are some
だからいくつかあります
Then there are some very detailed information about our local radar in Taiwan, etc.
それから、台湾の現地レーダーなどについての非常に詳しい情報もございます。
Our weather analysts may use a higher amount
当社の気象アナリストはより多くの量を使用する可能性があります
Then in other countries because they don't have the first line to see these materials
次に、他の国では、これらの資料を最初に見ることができないため、
they may not be useful
役に立たないかもしれない
will be slightly different
若干異なります
So statistically speaking
つまり統計的に言えば
Currently there are different
現在は様々な
From the United States, Japan, Hong Kong, Beijing
アメリカ、日本、香港、北京から
South Korea wait until our Central Weather Bureau
韓国は中央気象局を待つ
The overall average level of the forecast of this typhoon
今回の台風の予報全体の平均レベル
Basically, if we talk about predicting the final level in Taiwan, it is probably the same order
基本的に、台湾の最終レベルを予測する場合、おそらく同じ順序になります。
about the same
ほぼ同じ
nothing special
特にない
That is to say, everyone is the same
つまり、みんな同じなんです
level
水準
At present, this level is about
現時点ではこのレベルくらいです
Average error of forecast for one day
1日の予測の平均誤差
perhaps
多分
average about nine
平均9個くらい
10 to 100 kilometers
10～100キロ
so
それで
This may not be a big problem for other countries like the United States
これは米国のような他の国にとっては大きな問題ではないかもしれない
because big
因為大
It is not a small issue for Taiwan
台湾にとってそれは小さな問題ではない
because
なぜなら
We predict to go to Hualien
花蓮に行くと予想しています
Maybe in Taitung, but also in Yilan or Taikeelung
台東かもしれないが、宜蘭や太基隆にもあるかもしれない
In addition, our vacation is based on counties and cities
さらに、私たちの休暇は郡や都市に基づいています
that's finer
それはいいです
are within the margin of error of this forecast.
この予測の誤差の範囲内です。
this is our difficulty
これが私たちの困難です
So I leave that question to
それでその質問は残しておきます
those two
あの二人
two seniors
二人の先輩
good
良い
that last question
最後の質問
No
いいえ
is there a last question
最後の質問はありますか
good
良い
Thanks
ありがとう
Professor Wu's very brilliant speech
呉教授の素晴らしいスピーチ
I've always been curious
私はいつも興味がありました
because we are in Taiwan
私たちは台湾にいるので
Exposure to typhoons since childhood
幼少期から台風にさらされる
The typhoon that I heard from childhood
子供の頃から聞いていた台風
That's what Professor Wu said at the beginning
呉教授が冒頭でそう言った。
It is the disaster brought by typhoon
台風がもたらした災害です
then i always
それから私はいつも
I am very curious, since the power of disasters brought by typhoons is so great
台風による災害の威力はとても大きいのでとても興味があります
Then believe that he also has such great energy
それなら彼も素晴らしいエネルギーを持っていると信じてください
Is there any way to convert the energy of this typhoon into kinetic energy beneficial to human beings?
この台風のエネルギーを人類に有益な運動エネルギーに変換する方法はあるのでしょうか？
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you for this simple
シンプルにありがとう
Let's talk about wind energy first
まずは風力エネルギーについて話しましょう
Yes indeed we have some so-called WinMill on the western or northern coast of Taiwan
はい、確かに台湾の西海岸または北海岸にいわゆる WinMill がいくつかあります。
When this rotates, electricity is generated
これが回転すると電気が発生します
But the current design of these things
しかし、これらのものの現在のデザインは
Basically, the wind speed must be below a certain wind speed.
基本的には一定の風速以下でなければなりません。
In fact, above a certain wind speed
実際、一定の風速以上になると、
basically dangerous to the operation of its machinery
基本的にその器具の操作には危険があります
it may break etc
壊れる可能性があるなど
it just won't work
それはうまくいきません
Therefore, the strong wind of the typhoon will completely shut down the device under that condition.
したがって、このままでは台風の強風により完全に停止してしまいます。
so useless
とても役に立たない
Then this may be limited by our modern technology for this typhoon.
そうなると、今回の台風では現代の技術では限界があるかもしれません。
With such a strong wind speed
こんなに強い風速で
We don't have a way to use that energy yet
私たちはそのエネルギーを活用する方法をまだ持っていません
it's really a pity
本当に残念です
But I haven't heard of it yet
でもまだ聞いたことがない
Is there any way to convert this part out
この部分を変換する方法はありますか
Then we can also imagine that in fact
そして、実際には次のように想像することもできます
For example, the normal storage of water in the reservoir can help generate electricity
たとえば、貯水池に水を通常貯留すると、発電に役立ちます。
But in fact when the typhoon comes
でも実は台風が来ると
sometimes it's time to drain
時々それは排水する時間です
so there is no way
だから仕方ない
do these many operations
これらの多くの操作を行う
So this type belongs to the very violent, violent, and temporary type.
したがって、このタイプは非常に暴力的で、激しく、一時的なタイプに属します。
how to use it
それの使い方
Personally, I still need a lot
個人的にはまだまだ必要なものがたくさんあります
There is still a lot of room for improvement to get to that city
あの都市に到達するにはまだ改善の余地がたくさんある
Some energy that can transform it from negative to positive and so on
マイナスからプラスに変えるエネルギーなど
That
それか
At present, some scientists think of a stream like black grass
現在、一部の科学者は小川を黒い草のようなものだと考えています
such a strong current
とても強い流れ
Can it also be partially converted into electricity?
部分的に電気に変換することもできるのでしょうか？
but these are watching
しかし、彼らは見ています
stage of planning
計画の段階
So these issues are indeed technological challenges
したがって、これらの問題は確かに技術的な課題です
I can only say this now
今はこれしか言えない
ok that time is up
はい、もう時間です
We are very grateful to Director Wu for his wonderful speech
素晴らしいスピーチをしてくれたウー監督にとても感謝しています。
I will also take him to invite you to visit him at National Taiwan University another day
また、別の日に台湾大学に彼を訪ねるよう招待するつもりです。
The Department of Meteorology of National Taiwan University came out of that Gongguan MRT station.
国立台湾大学気象学部は、その MRT 公館駅から誕生しました。
About 100 meters away
約100メートル離れたところ
There, the vicinity of Lu Mingtang is very beautiful
そこ、陸名堂の周りはとても美しいです
You can play with him
あなたは彼と一緒に遊ぶことができます
Okay, we thank Director Wu
ウー監督に感謝します